<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trust on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/tags/trust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in trust on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 04:21:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/tags/trust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people - snapshot</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 04:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</guid>
      <description>To easily remember the main ideas of my previous post, Teams are made of people, I thought of a representative word and a short alternative description for each of them:
 Vision. The team has a vision of what it tries to accomplish. It should to be clear what is the team’s purpose accompanied by a “grand vision” that everyone understands and resonates with. Individuality. The team is aware of and respects the individual differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 17:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</guid>
      <description>I think this is quite an obvious thing to say. At the same time, it is quite common to forget what this fact means. What does it mean that this team that provides a service, or builds a product or works on a project, what does it mean that it is made of people? And to the extent of that, what does it mean that the users or the stakeholders are also people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy at work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/19/autonomy-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 17:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/19/autonomy-at-work/</guid>
      <description>Full disclosure: I haven’t read Daniel Pink’s Drive yet, but that doesn’t mean I can’t talk about autonomy, one of the 3 elements of true motivation he writes about in his book.
If you ask any employer in the world right now, I hardly believe anyone will tell you (s)he wants to micro-manage people. So what does it mean to not micro-manage people? It means giving them the autonomy they need to do their job in the best way they consider doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>