<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>habits on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/tags/habits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in habits on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 04:21:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/tags/habits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people - snapshot</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 04:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</guid>
      <description>To easily remember the main ideas of my previous post, Teams are made of people, I thought of a representative word and a short alternative description for each of them:
 Vision. The team has a vision of what it tries to accomplish. It should to be clear what is the team’s purpose accompanied by a “grand vision” that everyone understands and resonates with. Individuality. The team is aware of and respects the individual differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 17:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</guid>
      <description>I think this is quite an obvious thing to say. At the same time, it is quite common to forget what this fact means. What does it mean that this team that provides a service, or builds a product or works on a project, what does it mean that it is made of people? And to the extent of that, what does it mean that the users or the stakeholders are also people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits for reducing interruptions</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/04/19/habits-for-reducing-interruptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/04/19/habits-for-reducing-interruptions/</guid>
      <description>In most of the companies I worked so far, we usually get a lot of interruptions. Everything is deemed important and our attention is stretched super thin between all kind of distractions. In the beginning it feels good, we are busy and we are being helpful, but after a while it gets exhausting. And the flow of requests never ends.
One of the big issues with a large number of interruptions is that we are forced to make a lot of small decisions tens of times a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits and every day work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/25/habits-and-every-day-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/25/habits-and-every-day-work/</guid>
      <description>After reading in the The Power of Habit about how militaries or football coaches use habits to train their soldiers or players to react fast in the field, I started wondering how much of this science we could use in our everyday “pencil-pushing” or “keyboard-smashing” knowledge work?
As Charles Duhigg puts it, a habit consists of three important elements: a cue, a routine and a reward. On top of that, you need a craving to drive the loop cue-routine-reward to repeat itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/10/10/habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 07:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/10/10/habits/</guid>
      <description>We are creatures of habit. I’m sure you heard this expression before.

But it’s actually true. We need routines and habits to give structure to our life. Of course, there are a few rebels out there, who are decided to live every day in a different way, but I’m sure that even they have a routine in their craziness.
We build routines around things we HAVE to do (or feel uncomfortable about) and they start with small things that we LIKE to do, just to compensate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>