<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 06:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Chiri&#39;s reading notes - issue 2, jan &#39;20</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2020/02/02/reading-notes-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 06:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2020/02/02/reading-notes-2/</guid>
      <description>This was another pretty diverse month when it comes to reading: there’s more about ageing, strange stories about policemen and bicycles, leadership and change or leadership for change, how you need to fall in order to raise yourself, and some small bits and pieces about depression, philosophy, gene editing, productivity tools and several others. Hope you enjoy them!
 Lifespan, Why We Age—and Why We Don&#39;t Have To, by David Sinclair As a follow-up to David&#39;s podcast with Kevin Rose, I read his book, wanting to find out more details about his theory on ageing and I was not disappointed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your own podcast transcription service</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2020/01/12/make-your-own-podcast-transcription-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2020/01/12/make-your-own-podcast-transcription-service/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of very interesting podcasts out there that I like to listen to, as much as time allows me to do so. But I noticed that I don&#39;t recall much out of them and I feel the need to go through them again. It would be great if all podcasts came with a transcript, so I can quickly revisit the parts that interest me. Unfortunately, making transcripts to your podcasts can be quite expensive, which is why most authors don&#39;t do so or put them behind a paywall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Chiri&#39;s reading notes - issue 1, dec &#39;19</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/12/31/reading-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 06:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/12/31/reading-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by several newsletters I follow and read regularly, like Brain Food by Farnam Street, I decided to start my own little experiment in sharing some of the things I learn during the month in a newsletter. Just in time before the end of the year, the first issue of Reading Notes is out! Talking about software development gone bad, gone good, entrepreneurship and parenting, ageing and genetics and a system of taking notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The challenge of helping others</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/10/20/the-challenge-of-helping-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/10/20/the-challenge-of-helping-others/</guid>
      <description>A book I&#39;ve been reading lately revealed to me how tricky helping relationships can be, even though we put ourselves in such relationships several times every day and we don&#39;t even realise it. There are many things we do automatically successfully and we don&#39;t even think about it. Because we have been trained for many years by society and parents how to do it correctly according to the common rules. Helping others is no exception: we have been taught to help people around us that are in need and be receptive to others&amp;rsquo; pain and distress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights and storing knowledge</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/07/04/highlights-and-storing-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 20:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/07/04/highlights-and-storing-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago I was writing about a routine I setup to manage and refresh highlights from books and articles. In the meantime, I have adjusted it a little bit, removed some services and added some others. Let&#39;s start with the bits that didn&#39;t work that well.
Highlights from articles As much as I liked the flow with sending articles weekly from Pocket to Kindle using a service named aptly Pocket2Kindle, I soon became swamped with articles pending on my Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resurface highlights from books and articles you&#39;ve read in the past</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/03/04/resurface-highlights-from-books-and-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 20:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/03/04/resurface-highlights-from-books-and-articles/</guid>
      <description>In the last years, I&#39;ve been reading a fair amount of books. Besides that, I&#39;ve been wanting to read more interesting articles and blogs, which is why I started using Pocket for almost a year now. At the same time, I&#39;ve kept trying all kind of routines that would make me remember more from what I read. In the next paragraphs, I&#39;m going to describe what I am currently doing and although it is not perfect, it feels the best so far, considering I don&#39;t have much time to invest in revisiting these reads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/now/</guid>
      <description>What am I thinking or doing now:
 DevOps and Continuous Delivery consultant at Eficode Praqma. Chopping wood and carrying water every day and thinking about personal growth and what is the meaning of it all? Enthusiastic member of the Farnam Street Learning Community. Practicing lots of Rocket Yoga, because it helps quiet the mind. 🙏 Constantly thinking about how to improve working environments and help people be happier at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On meditation and journaling</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 14:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</guid>
      <description>Meditation For some time now (months) I have been meditating and journaling every day. I find this combo very useful for keeping myself on track with what I want to achieve and also be more present and balanced during the day.
I started playing around with the idea of meditating several years ago when I read Search Inside Yourself by Chade-Meng Tan, but it didn’t stick. I tried it several times again in the more recent years and I found it hard to practice every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept gravity and let go of your anchors</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/02/accept-gravity-and-let-go-of-your-anchors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/02/accept-gravity-and-let-go-of-your-anchors/</guid>
      <description>There are a couple of concepts I learned about recently, while reading “Designing your life” by Bill Burnett and Dave Evans. These are not part of the main idea of the book, but I found them as powerful as they are simple.
Gravity problems A gravity problem is a problem that is not actionable. If you see gravity as a problem and you decide to fight it, to “solve” it, you will realise sooner or later that it is unsolvable and you would be far off better with accepting it as a reality and find ways to work around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three great books to start the year</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/04/23/three-great-books-to-start-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 18:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/04/23/three-great-books-to-start-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Every year, I manage to read one or two books that get my mind going and give me ideas that I could either apply right away or that set me on a larger path of discovery. One or two out of tens, or to be more specific, last year, out of thirty. I started to look into ways I could organise notes and ideas that I find in books in a better way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetEnt Tech Meetup: How to go from zero to sixty in nineteen years by Woody Zuill (@WoodyZuill), 17 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/17/how-to-go-from-zero-to-sixty-in-nineteen-years-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 19:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/17/how-to-go-from-zero-to-sixty-in-nineteen-years-meetup/</guid>
      <description>After meeting Woody in a number of workshops and presentations about MOB programming, it was an unique and interesting opportunity to watch him talk about a different topic. He gave an inspiring talk about randomness, confirmation bias, serendipity, learning, experimenting, or as he called it “stumbling purposely and purposeful stumbling”. All of these coming from his own life experience, with a melange of personal stories, wise words and simply beautiful drawings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 3 - 6 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/15/lean-agile-scotland-day-3-6-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/15/lean-agile-scotland-day-3-6-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>The third day of LAScot was a little bit shorter for me, because I chose to come back to Stockholm on the same day. That gave me just enough time to see the keynote and @JoakimSunden’s talk about the “Spotify Model”.
Keynote: Awesome Superproblems by Luke Hohmann (@ LukeHohmann) Luke’s keynote was very inspiring. He demonstrated how our experience in building products and services can be used in other domains and parts of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What newsletters I happily open my mailbox to?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/15/what-newsletters-i-happily-open-my-mailbox-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 09:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/15/what-newsletters-i-happily-open-my-mailbox-to/</guid>
      <description>I have the impression that the general feeling towards the notion of newsletters is somewhere close to idea of spam. Lots of ads, poor content and usually showing up in your inbox without requesting it or without realising you have subscribed to it (check the tiny little checkboxes at the bottom of the forms!)
But there are exceptions, here are the newsletters that I am always happy to receive and actually look forward to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 2 - 5 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/12/lean-agile-scotland-day-2-5-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 17:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/12/lean-agile-scotland-day-2-5-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>One of the tricky parts of LAScot was getting hold of the tokens for tracks 3 to 5, which were not filmed and required a token to get access. Or you could “risk” it and drop by anyway, maybe someone changes his/her mind or there is some room left. In all the workshops I’ve been at, there were always extra people accommodated into the room.
These being said, on the first day I completely forgot about the tokens, although I was pretty early in the conference centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 1 - 4 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/09/lean-agile-scotland-day-1-4-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 19:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/09/lean-agile-scotland-day-1-4-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>This year was the first time I attended LAScot and I had high expectations from it. I wasn’t disappointed even just one bit!
I enjoyed the relaxed and friendly atmosphere. There is no right and there is no wrong, no superior or inferior, there’s just sharing, learning and lots of fruitful conversations. It’s the perfect environment for nurturing old friendships and growing new ones on the ground of common interests and a passion for the diverse fields that constitute and contribute to the knowledge work most of us are doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development Metrics by Dave Nicolette</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/09/22/software-development-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 13:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/09/22/software-development-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: https://davenicolette.wordpress.com/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Software-Development-Metrics-Dave-Nicolette/dp/1617291358 My rating: ★★★★★  Some thoughts Very good overview of metrics to be used in software development. I liked the structure of the book and how the metrics were split between metrics used for steering, improvement or both and what is particular when used for one or another.
I printed these metrics on paper cards, on one side the name and what they apply to (approach, process-model and delivery mode) and on the other side the notes specific to each purpose (steering or improvement).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radical Candor: Be a Kick-Ass Boss Without Losing Your Humanity by Kim Scott, 2017</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/09/03/radical-candor-be-a-kick-ass-boss-without-losing-your-humanity-by-kim-scott-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 12:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/09/03/radical-candor-be-a-kick-ass-boss-without-losing-your-humanity-by-kim-scott-2017/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: https://www.radicalcandor.com Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Radical-Candor-Kim-Scott/dp/B01KTIEFEE My rating: ★★★★★  Some thoughts Radical Candor or something with similar principles is essential for everyone to use in the work place to create connections with the others and learn and improve. It is also something that can require a lot of conscious effort to accomplish. But also to some it comes naturally in part. While reading the book, I remembered situations from my experience when I could&#39;ve reacted in a better way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefighting in software development</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/08/06/firefighting-in-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 14:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/08/06/firefighting-in-software-development/</guid>
      <description>The main duty of a developer is to build and improve features of a service or a product, either through big-bang releases or through continuous delivery. The second most time consuming activity (besides meetings, of course) in the life of a developer is fixing bugs and eliminating tech debt.
Bugs and tech debt have the nasty habit of generating urgent issues that prevent a service to function properly. When these happen, developers need to take immediate actions to bring back the service in a state of normality, as much as possible, as fast as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software down!!!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/08/06/software-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 14:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/08/06/software-down/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, my first impulse when the service I’m developing is malfunctioning is to jump right on it and try to fix it. But while I do that, I can’t help thinking about who is affected by it and how bad and if they will notice it. Then there’s the first five to ten minutes of the investigation, when I realise how far I am from finding a solution, yet, I keep thinking “Almost there, almost there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people - snapshot</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 04:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</guid>
      <description>To easily remember the main ideas of my previous post, Teams are made of people, I thought of a representative word and a short alternative description for each of them:
 Vision. The team has a vision of what it tries to accomplish. It should to be clear what is the team’s purpose accompanied by a “grand vision” that everyone understands and resonates with. Individuality. The team is aware of and respects the individual differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 17:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</guid>
      <description>I think this is quite an obvious thing to say. At the same time, it is quite common to forget what this fact means. What does it mean that this team that provides a service, or builds a product or works on a project, what does it mean that it is made of people? And to the extent of that, what does it mean that the users or the stakeholders are also people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Enlightenment: How Meditation Works by Shinzen Young, 2016</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://www.shinzen.org Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Science-Enlightenment-How-Meditation-Works-ebook/dp/B01KUGQYJO My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts Mindfulness and meditation are trendy. Or maybe that’s just my impression. There are many trainings and meditation experts out there, luring you to the places of clarity and tranquility, ability of getting over stressful and painful experiences in an easier way and experiencing life in a richer way.
I don’t know from a personal experience this to be a truthful promise, but that doesn’t mean it is not true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile is also about people</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 16:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</guid>
      <description>This has been probably said millions of times until now, but maybe it wouldn’t hurt to say it once more: agile is also about people.
The promise of agile is that, if applied “properly”, it will “accelerate development cycles, reveal code defects earlier, decrease overall project risk, and allow faster response to customer needs and changing business priorities” to quote one of the Google results.
And I don’t think anyone is really doubting that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits for reducing interruptions</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/04/19/habits-for-reducing-interruptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/04/19/habits-for-reducing-interruptions/</guid>
      <description>In most of the companies I worked so far, we usually get a lot of interruptions. Everything is deemed important and our attention is stretched super thin between all kind of distractions. In the beginning it feels good, we are busy and we are being helpful, but after a while it gets exhausting. And the flow of requests never ends.
One of the big issues with a large number of interruptions is that we are forced to make a lot of small decisions tens of times a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship: play for the long game</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/27/mentorship-play-for-the-long-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/27/mentorship-play-for-the-long-game/</guid>
      <description>One of the many wonderful game techniques I found out about in Yu-Kai Chou’s Actionable Gamification is about Mentorship (Game Technique #61).
Yu-Kai came up with a more elaborate “motivation framework” which has its roots in his research and other people’s research in why some games are so addictive. The Octalysis framework consists of 8 core drives that could be used to explain or design different experiences or products and how much they motivate people in one way or the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits and every day work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/25/habits-and-every-day-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/25/habits-and-every-day-work/</guid>
      <description>After reading in the The Power of Habit about how militaries or football coaches use habits to train their soldiers or players to react fast in the field, I started wondering how much of this science we could use in our everyday “pencil-pushing” or “keyboard-smashing” knowledge work?
As Charles Duhigg puts it, a habit consists of three important elements: a cue, a routine and a reward. On top of that, you need a craving to drive the loop cue-routine-reward to repeat itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy at work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/19/autonomy-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 17:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/19/autonomy-at-work/</guid>
      <description>Full disclosure: I haven’t read Daniel Pink’s Drive yet, but that doesn’t mean I can’t talk about autonomy, one of the 3 elements of true motivation he writes about in his book.
If you ask any employer in the world right now, I hardly believe anyone will tell you (s)he wants to micro-manage people. So what does it mean to not micro-manage people? It means giving them the autonomy they need to do their job in the best way they consider doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product vision and technical vision and something extra</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/12/product-vision-and-technical-vision-and-something-extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/12/product-vision-and-technical-vision-and-something-extra/</guid>
      <description>Take into consideration the following scenarios:
Scenario 1 Caleb is a product owner which works with a software development team in a successful product company. Caleb has a grand vision for the product that he is responsible for in the company. It is a vision that will probably never see the light of day exactly in the shape he imagines it right now, but maybe somewhere along the lines. In order to make this vision happen, Caleb works closely together with Dave, the tech lead of the development team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you micro-manage much?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know about you, but in my experience until now, there were situations where I felt micro-managed. And I hated it. Badly. It frustrated me. I didn’t understand why I was treated like that and I didn’t like the implications it had on the perceived quality of my work.
Doesn’t my boss think I’m capable? If you’re someone who cares about their work, having a boss who micro-manages you is not a good sign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/06/the-coaching-habit-say-less-ask-more-change-the-way-you-lead-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 18:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/06/the-coaching-habit-say-less-ask-more-change-the-way-you-lead-forever/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://www.boxofcrayons.biz/the-coaching-habit-book/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01BUIBBZI/ My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts The book is an elaboration of a simple trick: try to listen more and ask questions, rather than directly giving advice. I enjoyed the lecture of the book and the explanations of the 7 questions. Like all this kind of advice, I believe it is worth starting practicing the original questions to get an understanding of what are their effects and then start coming up with your own questions that have the same effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership and Self-Deception: Getting Out of the Box by The Arbinger Institute</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/12/19/leadership-and-self-deception-getting-out-of-the-box-by-the-arbinger-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 18:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/12/19/leadership-and-self-deception-getting-out-of-the-box-by-the-arbinger-institute/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: https://arbinger.com/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00GUPYRUS/ My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts I think The Arbinger Institute are on to something. It is still not 100% clear for me how someone gets in the box in the workplace, but I can definitely recognise the situation where one would throw trash at the company, without a clear understanding of why and what is the actual problem. It is easier to throw trash at something or someone else than criticising yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>drunkenpmradio - Having Empathy For Your Project - w/ Patrice Colancecco Embry [podcast]</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/drunkenpmradio-having-empathy-for-your-project-w-patrice-colancecco-embry-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 16:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/drunkenpmradio-having-empathy-for-your-project-w-patrice-colancecco-embry-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Link: https://alexchiri.com/post/drunkenpmradio-having-empathy-for-your-project-w-patrice-colancecco-embry-podcast
My notes: Treat a project with empathy.
As a PM talk about good things with &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo; and about negative with &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;.
As a PM you have to be positive about the project and believe that will succeed.
Do not talk bad about the project until the end. Allow yourself in the post-mortem to hate the project a little bit.
You should be positive and shove the negative at the end without looking like you fake it or you are not genuine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octalysis, self-deception, Cynefin and Slickyboards - Interesting! (Nov&#39;16)</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/octalysis-self-deception-cynefin-and-slickyboards-interesting-nov16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 16:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/octalysis-self-deception-cynefin-and-slickyboards-interesting-nov16/</guid>
      <description>Dust has settled on my blog lately. Writing stuff for the Internet is not my priority, no matter how much I enjoy it. I did decide to try something though: to briefly write about interesting things I found out every month. Like a newsletter about nothing and about everything, a mixed bag of new and old things I think are worth sharing. So here it is: Interesting!, Nov’16 edition!
Contents  * Octalysis, an actionable gamification framework * Self-deception and why it is so important for leaders and not only * Cynefin (pronounced _ku-nev-in_) framework for decision making * Slickyboards and Slickynotes, cheap convenient alternative for home whiteboards and static post-its  Games and what can we learn from why we play them Understanding what motivates people to do things is a pretty interesting problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My reading routine</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/05/my-reading-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 14:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/05/my-reading-routine/</guid>
      <description>Fiction or non-fiction? I’m always on the lookout for new things, so I’m constantly reading and learning stuff. I noticed that I cannot read always non-fiction, because it is usually harder to digest, so I only do that in the morning (usually in the subway ride to work) when my mind is fresh.
At the same time, if I only read non-fiction, I feel like I am always thinking about the things I am reading and my mind doesn’t get to disconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actionable Gamification - Beyond Points, Badges, and Leaderboards</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/10/23/actionable-gamification-beyond-points-badges-and-leaderboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/10/23/actionable-gamification-beyond-points-badges-and-leaderboards/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://yukaichou.com/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Actionable-Gamification-Beyond-Points-Leaderboards/dp/1511744049 My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts I like the Octalysis framework and its concepts. I think it makes sense and can be applied in pretty much anything related to people. The book has A LOT of well known examples which makes it easier to understand the basics.
I find it pretty difficult to internalize the meaning and the effects of the core drives, especially when combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum: The Art of Doing Twice the Work in Half the Time by Jeff Sutherland, 2014</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/09/29/scrum-the-art-of-doing-twice-the-work-in-half-the-time-by-jeff-sutherland-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 17:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/09/29/scrum-the-art-of-doing-twice-the-work-in-half-the-time-by-jeff-sutherland-2014/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: https://www.scruminc.com/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Scrum-Doing-Twice-Work-Half/dp/038534645X My rating: ★★★☆☆(3/5)  Some thoughts I enjoyed reading this book, it is quite an easy read, which you wouldn&#39;t expect after you go through the Scrum Guide. It goes through the origins of Scrum and the concepts behind it. It is filled with success stories, projects that were not going that well (now that&#39;s an understatement), like the Sentinel project of the FBI, and how applying Scrum to them improved their outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFH 043: The Agile Mindset with Gil Broza</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/09/13/afh-043-the-agile-mindset-with-gil-broza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 16:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/09/13/afh-043-the-agile-mindset-with-gil-broza/</guid>
      <description>Link: http://ryanripley.com/afh-043-the-agile-mindset-with-gil-broza-podcast/
As my memory doesn&#39;t seem to help me a lot with all this content around, I decided to start to create notes for podcasts as well. A little bit behind with my book notes and my podcast listening, but I&#39;m starting to catch up.
Notes
Too many agile implementations are not greatly exciting and not yielding great results
Most important for cultivating an agile mindset
 * Start with basic awareness of what it is - what do we mean when we say agile * Why do we want these things - agile is not just for better/cheaper/faster, but to delight the customers  A lot of people think that agile is the new standardised process and it is not a process nor standardised</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My personal map</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/28/my-personal-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 08:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/28/my-personal-map/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Nikoletta&#39;s post and Jurgen Appelo&#39;s Management3.0 concept of Personal Maps, I decided to do one for myself. So if you want to know a bit more about me, go check it out, either above or at this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coaching Agile Teams: A Companion for ScrumMasters, Agile Coaches, and Project Managers in Transition (Addison-Wesley Signature Series (Cohn)) by Lyssa Adkins, 2010</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/07/coaching-agile-teams-a-companion-for-scrummasters-agile-coaches-and-project-managers-in-transition-addison-wesley-signature-series-cohn-by-lyssa-adkins-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/07/coaching-agile-teams-a-companion-for-scrummasters-agile-coaches-and-project-managers-in-transition-addison-wesley-signature-series-cohn-by-lyssa-adkins-2010/</guid>
      <description>Book details  * Author link: [http://www.coachingagileteams.com/](http://www.coachingagileteams.com/) * Amazon link: [https://www.amazon.com/Coaching-Agile-Teams-ScrumMasters-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321637704](https://www.amazon.com/Coaching-Agile-Teams-ScrumMasters-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321637704) * My rating: ★★★★★ (5/5)  Some thoughts In a world where agile is mostly understood as processes, Lyssa Adkins includes in it also the human part. So an agile coach doesn&#39;t just take care of the process, but coaches and mentors the team and the people in it, to be better at agile, by also taking a look at the human side of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Guide Refresh July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/29/scrum-guide-refresh-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 11:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/29/scrum-guide-refresh-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>On 6th of July, a refreshed version of the Scrum Guide was released in a live webinar by Ken Schwaber and Jeff Sutherland.
The refresh basically consists in adding the Scrum values into the guide, the values as they were featured in the last chapter of the first book on Scrum (Agile Software Development with Scrum). Ken and Jeff identified these values while working at Patient Keeper and consider them to be very important to a successful Scrum adoption in companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFH 042: The Grows Method for Adopting Agile Software Develpoment</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/16/afh-042-the-grows-method-for-adopting-agile-software-develpoment-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/16/afh-042-the-grows-method-for-adopting-agile-software-develpoment-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Link: http://ryanripley.com/afh-042-the-grows-method-for-adopting-agile-software-development-podcast/
As I&#39;ve heard someone recently say, the amount of new Agile methods or methodologies is competing with the number of new JavaScript frameworks that pop up every now and then. When it comes to new Agile methods, they all usually have certain things in common (the Agile principles) but they come with a twist.
When it comes to Grows, as far as I understood from the podcast, the twist comes from the short feedback loops, involvement of executive roles, the tech best practices and the gradual development of the method in 5 stages (modelled after the Dreyfus Model of Skill Acquisition).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here it comes!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/19/here-it-comes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 14:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/19/here-it-comes/</guid>
      <description>The quiet Before it arrives, everything is pretty calm. There&#39;s the occasional walker and the soothing sound of the fountain, but not much else. Everything else is synchronised with its arrival. The majestic metal runner that brings people to their destination.
You wouldn&#39;t expect anything grandiose to happen, judging by how everything looks like. Some beggars at the entrance of the supermarket, one or two shoppers jumping from one deal to another, a couple of bored taxis standing by in the station and a homeless drinking his life from cheap beer cans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>agile info?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/11/agile-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/11/agile-info/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I added a few new sources of agile info (and not only) into my RSS reader and I would like to share them with you:
 * [https://www.reddit.com/r/agile/](https://www.reddit.com/r/agile/) * [https://www.reddit.com/r/softwaredevelopment/](https://www.reddit.com/r/softwaredevelopment/) * [http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/](http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/) * [http://blog.crisp.se/](http://blog.crisp.se/) * [http://www.svpg.com/articles/](http://www.svpg.com/articles/) * [http://www.jrothman.com/blogs/](http://www.jrothman.com/blogs/) * [http://ryanripley.com/agile-for-humans/](http://ryanripley.com/agile-for-humans/)  If you didn’t know, you can transform any reddit url in an RSS feed url by adding .rss at the end. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I added RSS</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/18/i-added-rss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 16:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/18/i-added-rss/</guid>
      <description>Not much to say about this. Felt like implementing something in 1-2 hours and this seemed like a good candidate. So here it goes, I now have RSS feed, I only need readers and will to write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Project Management Triangle must die!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/17/the-project-management-triangle-must-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 09:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/17/the-project-management-triangle-must-die/</guid>
      <description>John Ferguson Smart and Jan Molak in an article I stumbled upon today:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&amp;quot;On time, in scope and in budget&amp;quot;. This is the refrain of countless project managers on their LinkedIn profiles: it is the badge of the successful project manager, and they wear it with pride. It is also a misguided and dangerous idea that invariably encourages a short-sighted and bureaucratic mind-set, detrimental to both project teams and the organisations they serve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Cafe Episode 62 - Mary and Tom Poppendieck</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/devops-cafe-episode-62-mary-and-tom-poppendieck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/devops-cafe-episode-62-mary-and-tom-poppendieck/</guid>
      <description>Listened recently to this episode from Devops Cafe Podcast which is loaded with useful information and references. Besides the ones found in the page of the episode, I extracted the ones below:
 * [Lean Product and Process Development](http://www.amazon.com/Lean-Product-Process-Development-Allen/dp/1934109134) * [Product Development Performance](http://www.amazon.com/Product-Development-Performance-Organization-Management/dp/0875842453) * [Implementing Lean Software Development: From Concept to Cash](http://www.amazon.com/Implementing-Lean-Software-Development-Concept/dp/0321437381) * [Value stream mapping](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Value_stream_mapping) * [The Lean Startup](http://www.amazon.com/The-Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous/dp/0307887898) * [Personal Kanban](http://www.amazon.com/Personal-Kanban-Mapping-Work-Navigating/dp/1453802266) * [Building Microservices](http://www.amazon.com/Building-Microservices-Sam-Newman/dp/1491950358) * [Two Pizza Team](http://www.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052970203914304576627102996831200) * [Adrian Cockroft](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procrastinating by getting distracted</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/procrastinating-by-getting-distracted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 15:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/procrastinating-by-getting-distracted/</guid>
      <description>Attention is a precious thing these days. Emails, Facebook notifications, playlist notifications, colleague asking for help, loud neighbours, annoying ad and so many others, they are all running your power of concentration really low.
There are all kind of discussions about how knowledge workers have a hard time nowadays to produce &amp;lsquo;deep work&#39;, the kind of work and thinking that is required when trying to solve difficult and profound problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StackOverflow fun with ReactJS</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/03/07/stackoverflow-fun-with-reactjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 18:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/03/07/stackoverflow-fun-with-reactjs/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Dan Abramov&amp;lsquo;s tweet and with a desire to get better at ReactJS, this weekend I became a little bit more active on StackOverflow.
 The best way to learn a technology is to open its tag on StackOverflow and start helping people. This never failed me. 🙏
 — Dan Abramov (@dan_abramov) March 2, 2016I answered several ReactJS questions as best as I could and I gotta tell you, it&#39;s crazy addictive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t you do story mapping in your agile projects?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/28/why-dont-you-do-story-mapping-in-your-agile-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 18:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/28/why-dont-you-do-story-mapping-in-your-agile-projects/</guid>
      <description>Story maps is a concept made popular by Jeff Patton and he started using them professionally before he even started to call them story maps. They were born from the need of having a better way of approaching complex agile projects, one that gives them a better chance to be successful.
They&#39;re not sliced bread But they&#39;re really close. I&#39;ve started using story maps a few months ago and I find them a very useful tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective memory</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/selective-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 11:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/selective-memory/</guid>
      <description>Madiha Bhatti about basically racism:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t create a sense of urgency, foster a sense of purpose.</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/dont-create-a-sense-of-urgency-foster-a-sense-of-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/dont-create-a-sense-of-urgency-foster-a-sense-of-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Kimber Lockhart on a sense of purpose:
A strong sense of purpose manifests when a software engineer watches a potential customer struggle with a workflow and stays late to make the changes that make it easier. It shows itself when a designer spends their weekend on a few extra iterations because they felt engaged with the problem at hand and want to produce a better solution.
Turns out when you stop looking to create urgency, the passion and purpose latent in your team might just cause the right things to get done at just the right pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jfokus 2016 - Day 3: Git, parallelism, JCache, reactive and Boot</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/18/jfokus-2016-day-3-git-parallelism-jcache-reactive-and-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 17:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/18/jfokus-2016-day-3-git-parallelism-jcache-reactive-and-boot/</guid>
      <description>Sadly this was the last day of Jfokus and it was pretty cool!
Magic tricks with Git Third day of Jfokus started brilliantly with a very cool talk about Git given by Tim Berglund of DataStax.
 &amp;ldquo;Which of you are new to git?&amp;rdquo; Most of the room raises the hand.&amp;ldquo;Maybe you should leave!&amp;rdquo; #warmup #joke #jfokus #git pic.twitter.com/8y97ipeXu8
 — Alexandru Chirițescu (@alexchiri) February 10, 2016Tim showed us how to do a commit without actually using the git commit command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jfokus 2016 - Day 2: Talks, talks and some snoring</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/10/jfokus-2016-day-2-talks-talks-and-some-snoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 13:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/10/jfokus-2016-day-2-talks-talks-and-some-snoring/</guid>
      <description>Internet of things and things of Internet, Keynote I decided to try something different and so go to the IoT Keynote: IoT - an evolution from Internet of Screens to Internet of Things, done by Pawel Ostropolski from Intel. Basic gist: smart and connected devices are getting cheaper and cheaper and spread to all domains. In other words, they are becoming ubiquitous. It is now in the power of almost everyone to improve their life and the life of others by using technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jfokus 2016 - Day 1: Microservices and Mob programming</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/08/jfokus-2016-day-1-microservices-and-mob-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/08/jfokus-2016-day-1-microservices-and-mob-programming/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 2016, this is the microservices calling Microservices is one of the biggest buzz words of the moment. Being a very beginner in this topic, I decided to focus mostly on it through the Jfokus conference this year.
Chris Richardson&amp;lsquo;s tutorial, Introduction to microservices was comprehensive, taking us through the basic concepts, patterns and strategies behind them. Without going too much into details, there was lots of useful content and the presentation consists a good base to understand what are microservices about and give you several points to continue to find out more on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next week I’m going to Jfokus. Are you coming also?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/04/next-week-im-going-to-jfokus-are-you-coming-also/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 17:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/04/next-week-im-going-to-jfokus-are-you-coming-also/</guid>
      <description>Freshly moved to Stockholm, I am glad to go to Jfokus next week. There are quite a few talks, so it&#39;s good to be prepared. Here are the talks or workshops I&#39;m planning to attend to in each day:
Monday, 8th Feb  * 09:00 - 12:30: **Introduction to microservices**, Chris Richardson, Room C1 * 13:30 - 17:00: **Mob Programming Workshop**, Woody Zuill, Room C4  Tuesday, 9th Feb  * 09:15 - 10:30: **IoT Keynote: IoT - an evolution from Internet of Screens to Internet of Things**, Pawel Ostropolski - Intel, Room C1 * 11:00 - 11:15: **Presentation: Microservices: From dream to reality in forty five minutes**, Holly Cummins - IBM, Room A1 **Presentation: Moving Renewable Energy Embedded Systems Into the Cloud**, Mark Heckler - Pivotal * 13:00 - 13:50: **Presentation: Modelling Microservices at Spotify**, Petter Måhlén - Spotify, Room A1 * 14:00 - 14:50: **Presentation:How to defeat feature gluttony?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look ma, I built my own tiny blog in ReactJS!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/01/look-ma-i-built-my-own-tiny-blog-in-reactjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 17:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/01/look-ma-i-built-my-own-tiny-blog-in-reactjs/</guid>
      <description>When I started working almost daily with ReactJS a few months ago, I was pretty challenged (still am) with all the different modules to use and the concepts that I wasn&#39;t used with in the Java world. So I thought of a fun side-project with ReactJS to learn more and try some of the &amp;ldquo;crazy&amp;rdquo; things I couldn&#39;t really use at work at that point. Because I wanted to be able to do some link-blogging as well and Ghost (or any of the themes I liked) didn&#39;t facilitate it I decided to go wild and build my own blog in ReactJS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The client and the customer</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/01/24/the-client-and-the-customer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 08:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/01/24/the-client-and-the-customer/</guid>
      <description>Seth Godin explains the difference between a client and a customer
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;The customer buys (or doesn&#39;t buy) what you make. The client asks you to make something. The customer has the power to choose, but the client has the power to define, insist and spec. &amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;  It&#39;s an important distinction to make. I&#39;ve heard these terms being used pretty often with simply the meaning of the person/company that pays for a service or a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When you&#39;re moving houses...</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/10/18/when-youre-moving-houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 15:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/10/18/when-youre-moving-houses/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; you get this strange feeling, you sort of feel disoriented.
Maybe in our case was because things happened quite fast. Today we are in the apartment we lived for 3.5 years, 2 days later is completely empty and the morning after we hand in the keys to the agency, get in our car and drive away.
I was never really attached to things or places, but you develop habits and routines like using the same place to put your keys when you get in or the path you always take when doing your morning jogging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacation and work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/28/vacation-and-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 05:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/28/vacation-and-work/</guid>
      <description>I am always wondering how would it be if people wouldn&#39;t take holidays anymore.
Holidays always seem like the pleasant parts of life, where you get to travel, to spend more time with your family, to enjoy yourself more, to &amp;ldquo;recharge your batteries&amp;rdquo;. Once you&#39;re back to work, you need to readjust to the chaos, the routine and all that &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; entails.
Why does it have to be like this? Why can&#39;t you work and do holiday activities on a continuous basis, therefore removing the need for holidays?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you and goodbye Holland, heeellooo Sweden!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/27/thank-you-and-goodbye-holland-heeellooo-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 07:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/27/thank-you-and-goodbye-holland-heeellooo-sweden/</guid>
      <description>Immigrant life: reboot! So here we are, changing the type of the statistic we are. After 4 years and a few months since my wife and I were counted as moving in to The Netherlands and Amsterdam, we will be counted as leaving.
There&#39;s nothing out of the ordinary in our decision. Different groups of friends told me that&#39;s the norm, after 4 years in the country of tulips, you either stay quite longer or you leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple, light(-ish) and tasty evening snack</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/05/simple-light-ish-and-tasty-evening-snack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/05/simple-light-ish-and-tasty-evening-snack/</guid>
      <description>Fancy a delicious evening snack, but you don&#39;t want to feel too guilty about the extra calories?
Then I present you the Crunchy-Tomato-Garlicky-Madness!!! Isn&#39;t that a tongue twister? Never-mind, I still have to work on the marketing part, I&#39;ll figure it out later.
Ingredients Now go grab from your local grocery store the following and get munching (2 portions):
 1 large sized tomato (with the least plastic as possible) crackers / hard bread (more fibre, less unhealthy stuff) 3-4 cloves of fresh green garlic (not that frozen ages ago Chinese crap) chives dried tomato paste (optional, brings some extra flavour kick, also calories) shredded old cheese flakes (optional, but&amp;hellip;) olive oil lemon juice / vinegar salt  The process Get 2 crackers and put a thin layer of the tomato paste on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot in NL</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/03/hot-in-nl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 16:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/03/hot-in-nl/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I noticed since I&#39;ve been living in The Netherlands is that when the weather is hot, most drivers are going crazy. Aggressive over takes, speeding, poor checks on turns, not even talking about signalling! It&#39;s like a drivers gone mad convention.
But despite this behaviour there aren&#39;t many accidents or at least not many serious accidents[1] in The Netherlands yearly. Maybe also because there aren&#39;t too many hot days in the Dutch summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/02/stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/02/stuck/</guid>
      <description>Feeling stuck is not pleasant.
It feels like there&#39;s no direction to go towards to and there&#39;s not much to do. You get more and more frustrated with your current situation and you cannot think of anything else. You become obsessed.
Ironic, isn&#39;t it? To get stuck in your own thoughts. Because in reality very few situations are without exit. And I&#39;m not referring to those extreme cases here.
Every number of months or years you might get into a state where you know you have to change something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reality check</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/05/10/reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 10:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/05/10/reality-check/</guid>
      <description>Think of one of your employees. Imagine he asks you the following: how would you sell my job position to me, if I would be a candidate to be hired for it?
Would you be able to answer with an empty conscience?
What feedback would you get from your employee?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of (my) social media</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/22/future-of-my-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 12:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/22/future-of-my-social-media/</guid>
      <description>After sharing The Four Horsemen video (predictions about Google, Amazon, Facebook, Apple) on LinkedIn, I was asked by one of my connections if I would be willing to join him in preparing a blog that wants to predict the future of social media. Although I think it&#39;s a great idea (him who holds the power of information is always ahead), I declined, simply because I&#39;m no social media expert and more important, not an analyst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links and attention</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/14/links-and-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 12:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/14/links-and-attention/</guid>
      <description>I was reading the other day in some blinks (summaries of non-fiction books) from The Shallows, the following:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;Trying to juggle so much stimulus at once results in a loss of concentration, and makes it nearly impossible to read and extract information from long online texts. In fact, one experiment has shown that the more links a text includes, the less information participants could comprehend and remember after reading it. &amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;  And then I thought of my 7 habits article that I wrote a month or so ago, it has 21 (twenty one) links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescued by Pebble</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/02/24/rescued-by-pebble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 17:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/02/24/rescued-by-pebble/</guid>
      <description>I had a Pebble Steel watch for over a year now, but never took the time to put together an app or a watchface for it. Recently, I started testing RescueTime out of curiosity to see how much of my time is spent on &amp;ldquo;productive&amp;rdquo; things and how much on not so productive things.
Not much later I found myself refreshing the RescueTime dashboard every now and then to see how much I score on their stats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, there&#39;s streaming</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/02/19/so-theres-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 18:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/02/19/so-theres-streaming/</guid>
      <description>There are were and are a lot of discussions about Spotify not paying fair the artists for the number of streams that their creations get in the music streaming network. Now, to be honest, I don&#39;t know if Spotify is fair or not, there&#39;s plenty of pro articles as well as against this topic, but that&#39;s besides the point.
Let&#39;s say that Spotify doesn&#39;t pay fair, let&#39;s just assume that this is the uncontestable truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/25/so-whats-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 16:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/25/so-whats-next/</guid>
      <description>Here I am, at the end of the YourTurnChallenge! Uuuhuu, what a ride! __
I was pleasantly surprised to see that since about the half of the challenge I stopped using the list of subjects I prepared beforehand because I had other ideas I wanted to write about and those felt better than the ones on the list. That makes me feel very good about myself because I proved that I don&#39;t need to worry much about what to write as long as I write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 14:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>In a conversation with a friend (same friend, same conversation as a few days ago), he mentioned that everything that happens in the world is related basically to one question that each of us asks himself involuntarily: Who am I?
Some people identify with their job, with their hierarchy in the management ladder of a huge corporation. Some other identify with their religion or with their race or gender or &amp;hellip; you name it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have an idea</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 17:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>I have an idea about a revolutionary recipe website. Yeah, you read it right, a recipe website. Being a software engineer, you would think that it should be easy for me to build it and launch it, basically it&#39;s something I do every day for my employer. But as you might have found out, shipping is not that simple.
Stuck in preparation I had this idea for several years now and I started to make it happen, I think, about 4 or 5 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frustration</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/22/frustration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/22/frustration/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever felt like you&#39;ve been shoved into a corner and there&#39;s no way out? Well, there&#39;s always a way out, but maybe none that you would prefer taking? You could walk away at any time, but then you would loose all the work and effort you put into it. And then the rage fills you, because you feel helpless, handicapped. You don&#39;t like giving up, so you keep going, trying and trying and trying, maybe you will finally succeed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-preservation</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 17:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</guid>
      <description>I have thought many times why is it so difficult to admit that we were wrong. What makes it that hard to say &amp;ldquo;I&#39;m sorry, I was wrong&amp;rdquo;. Is it that important to always be right? Or is it just about not admitting that we were wrong?
&amp;ldquo;In fact, until we have to admit to someone that we were wrong, we aren&#39;t wrong, are we? I mean, that&#39;s all that matters, what the others think of us, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should things be simple, when they can be complicated?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/20/why-should-things-be-simple-when-they-can-be-complicated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 18:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/20/why-should-things-be-simple-when-they-can-be-complicated/</guid>
      <description>Or… should it be the other way around?
I’m always amazed about the amount of effort some people put in things that don’t need to be complicated. There is a general misconception that thorough and good work is recognised by the size of the deliverable. Therefore, insecure people will have the tendency to produce more and more complicated results, in an effort to compensate, to seem what they’re not.
Of course, we are often raised and educated that more is better, especially in communist educational systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/19/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 18:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/19/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people/</guid>
      <description>By accident, like most of the books I read, I stumbled upon Stephen Covey&#39;s book, The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People. It&#39;s one of those books, it&#39;s not enough to read them, or at least not just once, but you also should think deeply about the ideas in them and apply them into your life.
It&#39;s not the first time I mention Covey&#39;s book, I have shared fragments from it and even gave an extremely short summary of the main concepts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m joining the YourTurnChallenge</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/17/im-joining-the-yourturnchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/17/im-joining-the-yourturnchallenge/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you heard, maybe you didn&#39;t, but there&#39;s a new challenge in town!
It&#39;s called Your Turn Challenge and it&#39;s initiated by Winnie, the Special Projects Lead for Seth Godin. Now, it doesn&#39;t really matter who drives it, I&#39;ve been wanting for some time to increase the number of my blog posts and get them coming in a more regular fashion.
The challenge consists in blogging every day of next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/14/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 05:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/14/success/</guid>
      <description>I was having a discussion with one of my friends the other day…
7 habits I started telling him all about this good book[1] I just finished and that I found quite inspiring: you have these 7 habits everyone needs to develop, 3 for yourself, 3 for your relations with the others and 1 to grease the wheels for the others 6, to keep the thing going.
You have to be proactive, to be aware that you can make the choice of how you act, no matter what environment you’re in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactive or Reactive</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/03/proactive-or-reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 08:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/03/proactive-or-reactive/</guid>
      <description>Just a few things I read this a couple of days ago about reactive/proactive:
&amp;ldquo;Our behaviour is a function of our decisions, not our conditions&amp;rdquo;. If we choose to blame others for our conditions, we become reactive. &amp;ldquo;Proactive people are driven by values - carefully thought about, selected and internationalised values&amp;rdquo; while &amp;ldquo;Reactive people are driven by feelings, by circumstances, by conditions, by their environment&amp;rdquo;.
Reactive language:
 * There&#39;s nothing I can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make a change</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/24/lets-make-a-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 18:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/24/lets-make-a-change/</guid>
      <description>Some of these things are so simple that are easy to ignore, other are a little bit too abstract to act on them right away. It depends on each of us to act on the things we believe in, to make it our mission to fight for our ideas. Millions of books have been written about these subjects, yet most of the modern workers continue to ignore them. I’m going to add another drop to the ocean of recipes of presumed success, here it goes, take it with a bit of hope:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another unboxing of a Myo armband</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/07/yet-another-unboxing-of-a-myo-armband/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 16:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/07/yet-another-unboxing-of-a-myo-armband/</guid>
      <description>This is probably the gazillionth unboxing of a Myo that surfaced the Internet, so I won&#39;t bother you with too many comments. Let the images speak for themselves! :D
P.S. The unlock gesture, &amp;ldquo;pinky to thumb&amp;rdquo;, is killing me. Need.more.practice!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech Anywhere MX switch fixes, like an amateur</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/04/logitech-anywhere-mx-switch-fixes-like-an-amateur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 17:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/04/logitech-anywhere-mx-switch-fixes-like-an-amateur/</guid>
      <description>If you own one of these beauties, then get ready for some switches trouble. Don&#39;t get me wrong, I &amp;lt;3 this mouse, I have two (one for work, one for home), but seriously Logitech, couldn&#39;t you put better switches in it, so they don&#39;t die after less than a year of hard use? :-/
There are plenty of tutorials and videos about the issues with these switches and Google is your best pal there, so I won&#39;t get into details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes a leader</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/19/what-makes-a-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 08:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/19/what-makes-a-leader/</guid>
      <description>Like I probably said before, I read quite a lot of books, especially business and self-help books. I found out a few weeks ago about Daniel Goleman&amp;lsquo;s new book, What makes a leader?. The book is basically a collection of posts he did on Harvard Business Review along the years, starting with the one that has the same title as the book and was initially published in 1998.
The trouble with all these books is that if you don&#39;t do something concrete with them right away, you&#39;ll probably forget most of their content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Bundle or how I started reading more fiction</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 17:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Intro I have to say, I usually don&#39;t read a lot of fiction or fantasy books, as in, I rarely go and search for a specific fiction book in a store. It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t like the genre, but I seem to feel guilty because I don&#39;t read something &amp;ldquo;serious&amp;rdquo; instead. There&#39;s also the search of something to read, going through top 10 lists, New York Times best sellers list and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on the Rackspace Cloud Files action for Dropzone 3 and extras</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/26/more-on-the-rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3-and-extras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 18:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/26/more-on-the-rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3-and-extras/</guid>
      <description>Not so long ago, I released my first Dropzone 3 action and of course, I wrote about it on my blog!
After two weeks (back to the present) and some Ruby tutorials later, I improved the action and also added some more features to it.
Features, features, fea… One feature request I got on Twitter was to add support for custom domains (or CNAME records) for the remote containers:
— Alan Bush (@alanbush) August 13, 2014That was quite easy to do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rackspace Cloud Files action for Dropzone 3</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/12/rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 15:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/12/rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3/</guid>
      <description>Dropzone is a Mac OS X app which sits in the menu bar and that allows you to configure a series of actions. You can add these actions in a grid that is shown whenever you drag something on top of the icon in the menu bar. Then you can drop files on these actions and upload the files to Dropbox, Flickr, Amazon S3 and others or just keep them until you need them later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Live Deployment (Stories from Bitopia)</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/06/the-live-deployment-stories-from-bitopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 17:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/06/the-live-deployment-stories-from-bitopia/</guid>
      <description>It was a dark rainy night. You could hear some stray dogs howling, probably annoyed as well by the heavy rain. Everyone was at home. Well, except us, me and Marcel. We were getting ready for what was supposed to be my first live deployment since I joined Codis.
“It needs to be done during the night, when our users are busy fucking, living their pitiful worry-less lives! What do they care when we do updates, as long as everything WORKS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joel on software, work and management</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/25/joel-on-software-work-and-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/25/joel-on-software-work-and-management/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you&#39;ve heard about Joel Spolsky, or maybe his blog domain joelonsoftware.com sounds familliar. No? Nevermind!
He seems a smart and open minded person and he managed to (co-)found quite some cool companies, which gave birth to some really cool products (Stack Exchange or Trello anyone?)
He recently came back from his blogging retirement with an article about Trello. While I think Trello is a very good product, I was a bit more interested in the company culture reminded in his article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfishness</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/14/selfishness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 18:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/14/selfishness/</guid>
      <description>It seems that people are selfish by nature. All our instincts teach us to take care of ourselves and then of our species. If we would be reduced to our set of primal instincts, I would expect things to be quite simple. The game of life is known by everyone and the natural selection wins as always.
Imagine that one of these primitive humans could be tamed, like any other animals, by a superior creature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy of Coding 2014</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/03/07/joy-of-coding-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/03/07/joy-of-coding-2014/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I spent the entire day at the Joy of Coding conference, in Rotterdam. From my point of view, it was an example of how a coding conference should happen. Lots of sponsors, but nobody trying to get your personal data in exchange for a t-shirt or the promise of winning some sort of gadget. Focus was put on what matters: code, networking and sharing.
I have attended all the talks, here&#39;s a small part of what I took away from each of them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AsciiDoc writing</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/02/23/asciidoc-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/02/23/asciidoc-writing/</guid>
      <description>Context, context, it&#39;s all about context I started a little while ago to write a book. Yeah, I know, who would have thought, right? But that&#39;s besides the point.
Initially I used a writer specific app for Mac called Ulysses and while the app is really great, it has two disadvantages:
 * it is available only for Mac (and maybe in the future for iOS) * not geeky enough (I know this is a stretch for a second reason, but hey!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing up</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/01/02/standing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/01/02/standing-up/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I started using an improvised standing desk at home. I&#39;m sure some of you at least heard about the article about the 22$ standing desk made using an IKEA coffee table.
I&#39;m a classical couch potato most of the time and I&#39;m not a big fan of many sports, definitely not a fan of gyms or running, especially in a gym. I&#39;m also convinced that just by exchanging a sitting position with a standing position you accomplish almost nothing, exchanged an evil with maybe a smaller evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firecrackers and What the Hell?!!?!?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/01/01/firecrackers-and-what-the-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/01/01/firecrackers-and-what-the-hell/</guid>
      <description>Cover picture from ebeijing.gov.cn
After my &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo; to different lands, I couldn&#39;t fail to notice that Romania is not the only country where firecrackers can be heard intensively for the whole freakin&amp;rsquo; month of December. Children and children_not_anymore light large quantities of firecrackers on the streets, like some sort of way making themselves noticed, I guess?
Traditions I knew there is some sort of tradition in China, something about keeping evil spirits at bay, but my knowledge ended there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look ma&#39;, I cooked again!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/18/look-ma-i-cooked-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/18/look-ma-i-cooked-again/</guid>
      <description>After the last special, here comes another one. My mother used to cook a version of the following recipe when I was little. Ladies and gents, I give you Chiri Mama&#39;s Beef Delight!
Ingredients I don&#39;t know much about from what part of the cow every piece of meat comes from, so forgive me for not being really specific:
 * 600 grams of beef meat (I like it to have a bit of fat, gives more flavor) * 3 big peppers * 250 grams (basmati) rice (if you use a different rice, you might want to put less rice) * 1 big onion * 5-6 garlic cloves * half a glass of red wine * cooking olive oil * grilled paprikas (as a side dish)  How to First things first and that means you have to cut that cow down, medium slices, not too big, but not too small, you want to distinguish them from the rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>holder.js, a handy image placeholder generator</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/10/holder-js-a-handy-image-placeholder-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/10/holder-js-a-handy-image-placeholder-generator/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes when you&#39;re prototyping a new website or a new page, you would like to add a image placeholder, just to see how things fall into place.
You can use a service like placehold.it or a small javascript like holder.js, which spares the extra requests to an external server, not that in development this matters much.
For example, in order to generate the two placeholders below, you would only need to write the following HTML code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers can cook</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/09/developers-can-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/09/developers-can-cook/</guid>
      <description>Not that there&#39;s anyone there believing that developers cannot cook, but there&#39;s no harm in stating the obvious from once in a while[1]. So, here you go, Chiri&#39;s Chicken &#39;Sort Of&#39; Stew recipe:
Ingredients Now, you can make a stew out of pretty much anything, but today I chose the following ingredients:
 * 500 grams of chicken * 3 big peppers * 500 grams of &#39;shrooms (champignons) * 1 big onion * 1 can of peeled tomatoes * 5-6 garlic cloves  How to This is not rocket science, when it comes to stews, you have to put all the stuff together in a pot and let them boil for a while and you&#39;re done!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile publishing with Octopress and RaspberryPi</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/10/20/mobile-publishing-with-octopress-and-raspberrypi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/10/20/mobile-publishing-with-octopress-and-raspberrypi/</guid>
      <description>Preamble A few weeks ago scriptogr.am decided to suddenly change how their Markdown processor worked, making any HTML embedded in the Markdown posts worthless, among other things. So I woke up that my 2-readers-blog was looking like s**t, with content not being displayed[1], all because of the changes scriptogr.am did without any warning before.
These actions triggered some tweets to be sent, although I was already decided to move from scriptogr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourists in Amsterdam - Part I</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/10/01/tourists-in-amsterdam-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/10/01/tourists-in-amsterdam-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Being surprised by the incredible weather this weekend, we decided to walk around Amsterdam a bit, like any tourist would do.
Here&#39;s our journey from this Saturday, accompanied by photos and some explanations(TREASURE MAP), follow the pointers on the map to get an idea where the photos were taken:
1 Our starting point, close to Centraal Station, near the luxurious Amrath Hotel and its 7 Seas restaurant. Amazing pillow of clouds in the background, incredible weather for this end of September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch countryside</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/24/dutch-countryside/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/24/dutch-countryside/</guid>
      <description>A view from the countryside near the Zaanse Schans, a park known for its functional wind mills and traditional Dutch landscapes.

Taken on 1st of October, 2011 in The Netherlands
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you say no?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/16/do-you-say-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/16/do-you-say-no/</guid>
      <description>Cover picture from growingleaders.com
We all want to help other people, we like to be problem solvers, we want to be in the spotlight, no seems like a barrier
To start with a well-known geek joke[1], &amp;ldquo;there are 10 types of people in the world&amp;rdquo;, those who can say no and those who can not.
No(!), I&#39;m actually talking about those situations where you know you should say no, but you don&#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playful squirrels</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/15/playful-squirrels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/15/playful-squirrels/</guid>
      <description>A pair of playful squirrels somewhere on the Petřín hill, Prague, Czech Republic

Taken on 17th of September, 2008 in Czech Republic
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain cross</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/11/mountain-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/11/mountain-cross/</guid>
      <description>The cross on the &amp;ldquo;Caraiman&amp;rdquo; peak, Romania

Taken on 26th of December, 2006 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunset</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/08/sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/08/sunset/</guid>
      <description>The end of one of those hot summer days, &amp;ldquo;Lacul Morii&amp;rdquo;, Bucharest, Romania

Taken on 9th of June, 2009 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time traveling with the Java Calendar</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/08/time-traveling-with-the-java-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/08/time-traveling-with-the-java-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Playing with time in Java can be a tricky thing. Here&#39;s what happens when you use the Calendar class to make a trip back in time and back again:
UPDATE: I have tested this code only with the default GregorianCalendar. You should be aware that, depending on your Locale you might get a different Calendar implementation. Although they should behave the same, consider yourself warned! :)
Check the following code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country side</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/07/country-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/07/country-side/</guid>
      <description>I have been going through our photos recently and thought that some are nice to share. So I am gonna start doing this quite often. Here&#39;s the first:

Taken on 5th of June, 2010 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who knows what dinking is?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/04/who-knows-what-dinking-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/04/who-knows-what-dinking-is/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading an interesting book about the history of biking in the Netherlands written by an American. I have encountered some interesting facts.
First of all, what is dinking? I intend to clear this mystery as fast as possible, with a quote from TheFreeDictionary:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;dink adj (Clothing &amp;amp; Fashion) Scot and northern English dialect neat or neatly dressed vb Austral and NZ chiefly children&#39;s slang a. (tr) to carry (a second person) on a horse, bicycle, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giethoorn</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/01/giethoorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/01/giethoorn/</guid>
      <description>One of the most picturesque villages I have visited until now in the Netherlands, only for the ones who don&#39;t feel threatened by boats and water.
Giethoorn, this village in the province of Overijssel, is often called the Venice of the North and while far from me to make this kind of appreciations (I have never been to Venice, yet), I can say it is definitely one of the objectives you should not miss while in Holland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem solving and the random factor</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/27/problem-solving-and-the-random-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/27/problem-solving-and-the-random-factor/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A colleague of mine asked for my help, after spending hours on trying to figure out why he is getting the wrong results with his code. I went to his desk and in 5 minutes, problem was solved! You would be tempted to say, &amp;ldquo;Whoaaa, man, you&#39;re very good! Solving that dude&#39;s problem in a few minutes after he spent hours working it!&amp;quot;.
Well, actually I didn&#39;t do anything. My colleague fixed his problem on his own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A life protecting barrier for the Rotterdam area</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/25/a-life-protecting-barrier-for-the-rotterdam-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 07:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/25/a-life-protecting-barrier-for-the-rotterdam-area/</guid>
      <description>I have visited recently the Maeslantkering surge barrier in the Hoek van Holland area, near Rotterdam. It is an impressive construction with an important role: to protect lives.
But before I tell you more about the barrier, here&#39;s a short introduction about The Delta Project.
The reason After the big flood in Jan-Feb 1953 (in Dutch is called watersnoodramp) and the 1836 people who died because of it, things became clear for the Netherlands[1]: they needed to be better prepared for this kind of events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme of the month: Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/08/theme-of-the-month-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/08/theme-of-the-month-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>I have been recently reading about performance and what makes you better. The term of &amp;lsquo;deliberate practice&amp;rsquo; popped up more than once.
I&#39;m halfway through the book Talent Is Overrated: What Really Separates World-Class Performers from Everybody Else by Geoff Colvin and I found quite some interesting things while reading it.
We all know that in order to get better at something we have to practice. Well, it seems that it is not enough and in order to get best results we should engage in something called &amp;lsquo;deliberate practice&amp;rsquo; in a study from the &amp;lsquo;90s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You gotta&#39; love the Sunday evening news</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/07/22/you-gotta-love-the-sunday-evening-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/07/22/you-gotta-love-the-sunday-evening-news/</guid>
      <description>I had the dark thought of watching the news while visiting my relatives and friends in Romania and it happened to be a Sunday (yesterday). Here are a few of the subjects presented:
 * Son cuts his father&#39;s penis because he found him with his daughter in law naked, in bed! They presented extensive interviews of the neighbours and friends of the family affected by this damn affair. * The President was craving for some beer so he crashed a festival close to Bucharest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So good they can&#39;t ignore you by Cal Newport</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/07/22/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-by-cal-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/07/22/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-by-cal-newport/</guid>
      <description>With all the books out there that tell you to follow your passion, whichever that is, this book feels like a fresh breeze in a hot summer
Finding his/her passion is something that everyone dreams about. This is one of the main dilemmas when you are a freshman.
The labour market has changed in the last decade or so and there&#39;s more need for people with initiatives and who are creative, in any field of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great books</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/24/great-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/24/great-books/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve read some really great books in the last couple of years. Here&#39;s a list of those books.
The value of these books is relative to whatever the reader takes out from them. Just putting them in the &amp;lsquo;read&amp;rsquo; list of Goodreads won&#39;t make the reader rich, successful or in any way different.
Already read  * **Difficult Conversations: How to Discuss What Matters Most** by Douglas Stone, Bruce Patton, Sheila Heen * One of the best books I have read in the last period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much are we lying to ourselves?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/16/how-much-are-we-lying-to-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/16/how-much-are-we-lying-to-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>Random thoughts about self-inflicted lies.
I think that each and every one of us lies to himself at least a few times a day. From the &amp;ldquo;I&#39;ll go pick up dry cleaning tomorrow, it&#39;s too cold today&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;He doesn&#39;t have a clue what he says, you&#39;re cool, he&#39;s just jealous&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;hellip;
People who don&#39;t accept critics are probably keeping themselves in some sort of pedestal, where nobody can touch them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is a dance</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/02/08/life-is-a-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/02/08/life-is-a-dance/</guid>
      <description>I have discovered Alan Watts a few days ago and since then I have been going through the Youtube videos with his lectures. I like his way of putting things into words, it&#39;s a pleasure to listen and to think about his ideas. Here&#39;s one of my favorites that could be resumed to one simple idea: carpe diem!
[embed]https://www.youtube.com/embed/29atSZKbmS4[/embed]
I have tried to make a transcript of this video, couldn&#39;t grasp a couple of words, sorry for that!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type erasure and some Java bytecode</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/28/type-erasure-and-some-java-bytecode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/28/type-erasure-and-some-java-bytecode/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;ve worked with Java for a while, I&#39;m sure you&#39;ve heard about one of the things that Java does at compile time: type erasure. But you don&#39;t have to trust everybody by their word, you can check it by yourself!
As you know, when you &amp;ldquo;compile&amp;rdquo; your class, the .java file is transformed into a .class file, which is a binary file containing JVM operation codes (each operation is represented by a byte = bytecode).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contra</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/16/contra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/16/contra/</guid>
      <description>One of the main ideas of the famous TV show, House M.D., was that in order to generate good ideas, you have to challenge yourself or have people to challenge you at every step.
And I think this is the most valuable lesson which that show has to offer and it repeats it in every damn episode, for the duration of 8 seasons! It must be good!
Leaving House aside, challenge, if it&#39;s done in a constructive manner, it is very productive, otherwise it&#39;s just &amp;lsquo;contra&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank robbers and Java concurrency</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/14/bank-robbers-and-java-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/14/bank-robbers-and-java-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>Java 7 puts on the table some new tools for concurrency and its family of Executors. Here&#39;s my attempt of exemplifying their usage with a small bank robbers analogy.
Here&#39;s the thing: let&#39;s say you are a team of bank robbers and you want to pull up a heist on a bank. A team means multiple members and each can carry so much bags of money. Let&#39;s put in code a Heist, a Bank with not enough security and using the new ForkJoinPool, let&#39;s parallelize and distribute the tasks between robbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More or less</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/05/more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/05/more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>A bit of history I started using my parents old russian vinyl player when I was a bit older than 3 years old (or so I was told). We had a few tens of vinyls, most of them &amp;lsquo;classics&amp;rsquo; like Harry Belafonte, Elton John, Roxette, Abba and a bunch of children stories recorded for the radio, sometime in the &amp;lsquo;60s or &amp;lsquo;70s.
You could guess which were my favorites at that time, I knew them by heart and a day wouldn&#39;t pass without the player &amp;lsquo;booming&amp;rsquo; with children stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farming and Dependency Injection in Java</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/30/farming-and-dependency-injection-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/30/farming-and-dependency-injection-in-java/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s always good to revisit topics that you already touched before, the chance is that you will find out new things or remember forgotten ones.
So while I go over The Well-Grounded Java Developer, I intend posting here my own examples on different topics and techniques covered there.
Dependency Injection Today, the theme is going to be Dependency Injection. You probably know that there&#39;s a specification for this, namely JSR-330 and you surely know what Dependency Injection is (let&#39;s call it DI from now on).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown blogging</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/29/markdown-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/29/markdown-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Today, I switched to a static blog using Scriptogr.am and Dropbox. I thought it might be useful to share what I use to write articles on my new blog!
Sublime Text 2 My editor of choice for everything except advanced programming is Sublime Text 2, so I am going to tell you what customizations I did for Markdown.
First, you should install the following packages (I got inspired from this article):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gone static!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/29/gone-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 07:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/29/gone-static/</guid>
      <description>Having a small blog where you can ramble about whatever you want should be a simple thing, right? I mean you don&#39;t pay much to the host, they have installation scripts for any platform you like, you just buy a domain (if you want) and you start writing! Well, that&#39;s only in theory, at least for me.
It all started a few months ago with my domain alexchiri.ro just disappearing from the records of my host at that time, icebluehost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>val team = geek&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/11/17/val-team-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 09:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/11/17/val-team-geek/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s face it: a typical geek is not known for his social skills, best manners or his exquisite taste in clothes. Of course, most of the geeks are not typical either, but again most of them would prefer to be buried in bad code than holding a presentation or buy clothes for a fancy party with a dress code.
_Team Geek. A Software Developer&#39;s Guide to Working Well with Others_|Brian W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/10/10/habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 07:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/10/10/habits/</guid>
      <description>We are creatures of habit. I’m sure you heard this expression before.

But it’s actually true. We need routines and habits to give structure to our life. Of course, there are a few rebels out there, who are decided to live every day in a different way, but I’m sure that even they have a routine in their craziness.
We build routines around things we HAVE to do (or feel uncomfortable about) and they start with small things that we LIKE to do, just to compensate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Angel&#39;s Game by Carlos Ruiz Zafón</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/09/27/the-angels-game-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/09/27/the-angels-game-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</guid>
      <description>Shortly after finishing The Shadow Of The Wind, I received the second novel from the series.

David Martin. A boy that becomes a man too soon, due to some tragic events. He starts working for a living at a small age and for a low wage, constantly pressured by his condition and his dark past. What he doesn’t know is that the future is even darker, maybe too dark, if you ask me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficult conversations</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/09/16/difficult-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/09/16/difficult-conversations/</guid>
      <description>We all have difficult conversations everyday, be it with someone who steps in front of you in line or with your boss asking for a raise. Sometimes they don&#39;t end as we would have liked it, right?

How many times we think that the other party is to blame of the result? Well, that&#39;s normal, our self-conservation instinct does that to protect us of bad feelings. But that is not generally a good thing, because at the same time cancels any type of self analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow Of The Wind by Carlos Ruiz-Zafón</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/09/01/the-shadow-of-the-wind-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/09/01/the-shadow-of-the-wind-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</guid>
      <description>One of the best books I read in the last couple of months, it has all the right elements to be a successful novel.
I found out about this novel from a tweet of one of the people I&#39;m following. The tweet contained a quote that made me curious:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;People are evil. — Not evil, Fermín objected. Moronic, which isn&#39;t quite the same thing. &amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;  Now, after reading the book, I think this is one of the quotes that best describes the ultimate cause of the tragedy from this story Zafón presents to us: human nature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>