<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>me on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/tags/me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in me on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 08:07:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/tags/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My personal map</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/28/my-personal-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 08:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/28/my-personal-map/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Nikoletta&#39;s post and Jurgen Appelo&#39;s Management3.0 concept of Personal Maps, I decided to do one for myself. So if you want to know a bit more about me, go check it out, either above or at this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 14:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>In a conversation with a friend (same friend, same conversation as a few days ago), he mentioned that everything that happens in the world is related basically to one question that each of us asks himself involuntarily: Who am I?
Some people identify with their job, with their hierarchy in the management ladder of a huge corporation. Some other identify with their religion or with their race or gender or &amp;hellip; you name it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have an idea</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 17:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>I have an idea about a revolutionary recipe website. Yeah, you read it right, a recipe website. Being a software engineer, you would think that it should be easy for me to build it and launch it, basically it&#39;s something I do every day for my employer. But as you might have found out, shipping is not that simple.
Stuck in preparation I had this idea for several years now and I started to make it happen, I think, about 4 or 5 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech Anywhere MX switch fixes, like an amateur</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/04/logitech-anywhere-mx-switch-fixes-like-an-amateur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 17:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/04/logitech-anywhere-mx-switch-fixes-like-an-amateur/</guid>
      <description>If you own one of these beauties, then get ready for some switches trouble. Don&#39;t get me wrong, I &amp;lt;3 this mouse, I have two (one for work, one for home), but seriously Logitech, couldn&#39;t you put better switches in it, so they don&#39;t die after less than a year of hard use? :-/
There are plenty of tutorials and videos about the issues with these switches and Google is your best pal there, so I won&#39;t get into details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on the Rackspace Cloud Files action for Dropzone 3 and extras</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/26/more-on-the-rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3-and-extras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 18:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/26/more-on-the-rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3-and-extras/</guid>
      <description>Not so long ago, I released my first Dropzone 3 action and of course, I wrote about it on my blog!
After two weeks (back to the present) and some Ruby tutorials later, I improved the action and also added some more features to it.
Features, features, fea… One feature request I got on Twitter was to add support for custom domains (or CNAME records) for the remote containers:
[@alexchiri](https://twitter.com/alexchiri) [@aptonic](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rackspace Cloud Files action for Dropzone 3</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/12/rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 15:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/12/rackspace-cloud-files-action-for-dropzone-3/</guid>
      <description>Dropzone is a Mac OS X app which sits in the menu bar and that allows you to configure a series of actions. You can add these actions in a grid that is shown whenever you drag something on top of the icon in the menu bar. Then you can drop files on these actions and upload the files to Dropbox, Flickr, Amazon S3 and others or just keep them until you need them later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Live Deployment (Stories from Bitopia)</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/06/the-live-deployment-stories-from-bitopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 17:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/06/the-live-deployment-stories-from-bitopia/</guid>
      <description>It was a dark rainy night. You could hear some stray dogs howling, probably annoyed as well by the heavy rain. Everyone was at home. Well, except us, me and Marcel. We were getting ready for what was supposed to be my first live deployment since I joined Codis.
“It needs to be done during the night, when our users are busy fucking, living their pitiful worry-less lives! What do they care when we do updates, as long as everything WORKS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look ma&#39;, I cooked again!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/18/look-ma-i-cooked-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/18/look-ma-i-cooked-again/</guid>
      <description>After the last special, here comes another one. My mother used to cook a version of the following recipe when I was little. Ladies and gents, I give you Chiri Mama&#39;s Beef Delight!
Ingredients I don&#39;t know much about from what part of the cow every piece of meat comes from, so forgive me for not being really specific:
 * 600 grams of beef meat (I like it to have a bit of fat, gives more flavor) * 3 big peppers * 250 grams (basmati) rice (if you use a different rice, you might want to put less rice) * 1 big onion * 5-6 garlic cloves * half a glass of red wine * cooking olive oil * grilled paprikas (as a side dish)  How to First things first and that means you have to cut that cow down, medium slices, not too big, but not too small, you want to distinguish them from the rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers can cook</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/09/developers-can-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/09/developers-can-cook/</guid>
      <description>Not that there&#39;s anyone there believing that developers cannot cook, but there&#39;s no harm in stating the obvious from once in a while[1]. So, here you go, Chiri&#39;s Chicken &#39;Sort Of&#39; Stew recipe:
Ingredients Now, you can make a stew out of pretty much anything, but today I chose the following ingredients:
 * 500 grams of chicken * 3 big peppers * 500 grams of &#39;shrooms (champignons) * 1 big onion * 1 can of peeled tomatoes * 5-6 garlic cloves  How to This is not rocket science, when it comes to stews, you have to put all the stuff together in a pot and let them boil for a while and you&#39;re done!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile publishing with Octopress and RaspberryPi</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/10/20/mobile-publishing-with-octopress-and-raspberrypi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/10/20/mobile-publishing-with-octopress-and-raspberrypi/</guid>
      <description>Preamble A few weeks ago scriptogr.am decided to suddenly change how their Markdown processor worked, making any HTML embedded in the Markdown posts worthless, among other things. So I woke up that my 2-readers-blog was looking like s**t, with content not being displayed[1], all because of the changes scriptogr.am did without any warning before.
These actions triggered some tweets to be sent, although I was already decided to move from scriptogr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch countryside</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/24/dutch-countryside/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/24/dutch-countryside/</guid>
      <description>A view from the countryside near the Zaanse Schans, a park known for its functional wind mills and traditional Dutch landscapes.

Taken on 1st of October, 2011 in The Netherlands
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain cross</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/11/mountain-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/11/mountain-cross/</guid>
      <description>The cross on the &amp;ldquo;Caraiman&amp;rdquo; peak, Romania

Taken on 26th of December, 2006 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunset</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/08/sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/08/sunset/</guid>
      <description>The end of one of those hot summer days, &amp;ldquo;Lacul Morii&amp;rdquo;, Bucharest, Romania

Taken on 9th of June, 2009 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country side</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/07/country-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/07/country-side/</guid>
      <description>I have been going through our photos recently and thought that some are nice to share. So I am gonna start doing this quite often. Here&#39;s the first:

Taken on 5th of June, 2010 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A life protecting barrier for the Rotterdam area</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/25/a-life-protecting-barrier-for-the-rotterdam-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 07:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/25/a-life-protecting-barrier-for-the-rotterdam-area/</guid>
      <description>I have visited recently the Maeslantkering surge barrier in the Hoek van Holland area, near Rotterdam. It is an impressive construction with an important role: to protect lives.
But before I tell you more about the barrier, here&#39;s a short introduction about The Delta Project.
The reason After the big flood in Jan-Feb 1953 (in Dutch is called watersnoodramp) and the 1836 people who died because of it, things became clear for the Netherlands[1]: they needed to be better prepared for this kind of events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gone static!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/29/gone-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 07:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/12/29/gone-static/</guid>
      <description>Having a small blog where you can ramble about whatever you want should be a simple thing, right? I mean you don&#39;t pay much to the host, they have installation scripts for any platform you like, you just buy a domain (if you want) and you start writing! Well, that&#39;s only in theory, at least for me.
It all started a few months ago with my domain alexchiri.ro just disappearing from the records of my host at that time, icebluehost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>