<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agile on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>/categories/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agile on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:53:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 3 - 6 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/10/15/lean-agile-scotland-day-3-6-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/15/lean-agile-scotland-day-3-6-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>The third day of LAScot was a little bit shorter for me, because I chose to come back to Stockholm on the same day. That gave me just enough time to see the keynote and @JoakimSunden’s talk about the “Spotify Model”.
Keynote: Awesome Superproblems by Luke Hohmann (@ LukeHohmann) Luke’s keynote was very inspiring. He demonstrated how our experience in building products and services can be used in other domains and parts of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 2 - 5 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/10/12/lean-agile-scotland-day-2-5-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 17:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/12/lean-agile-scotland-day-2-5-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>One of the tricky parts of LAScot was getting hold of the tokens for tracks 3 to 5, which were not filmed and required a token to get access. Or you could “risk” it and drop by anyway, maybe someone changes his/her mind or there is some room left. In all the workshops I’ve been at, there were always extra people accommodated into the room.
These being said, on the first day I completely forgot about the tokens, although I was pretty early in the conference centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 1 - 4 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/10/09/lean-agile-scotland-day-1-4-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 19:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/09/lean-agile-scotland-day-1-4-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>This year was the first time I attended LAScot and I had high expectations from it. I wasn’t disappointed even just one bit!
I enjoyed the relaxed and friendly atmosphere. There is no right and there is no wrong, no superior or inferior, there’s just sharing, learning and lots of fruitful conversations. It’s the perfect environment for nurturing old friendships and growing new ones on the ground of common interests and a passion for the diverse fields that constitute and contribute to the knowledge work most of us are doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile is also about people</title>
      <link>/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 16:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</guid>
      <description>This has been probably said millions of times until now, but maybe it wouldn’t hurt to say it once more: agile is also about people.
The promise of agile is that, if applied “_properly_”, it will “accelerate development cycles, reveal code defects earlier, decrease overall project risk, and allow faster response to customer needs and changing business priorities” to quote one of the Google results.
And I don’t think anyone is really doubting that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t you do story mapping in your agile projects?</title>
      <link>/2016/02/28/why-dont-you-do-story-mapping-in-your-agile-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 18:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/28/why-dont-you-do-story-mapping-in-your-agile-projects/</guid>
      <description>Story maps is a concept made popular by Jeff Patton and he started using them professionally before he even started to call them story maps. They were born from the need of having a better way of approaching complex agile projects, one that gives them a better chance to be successful.
They&amp;rsquo;re not sliced bread But they&amp;rsquo;re really close. I&amp;rsquo;ve started using story maps a few months ago and I find them a very useful tool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>