<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agile on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agile on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 19:55:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NetEnt Tech Meetup: How to go from zero to sixty in nineteen years by Woody Zuill (@WoodyZuill), 17 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/10/17/how-to-go-from-zero-to-sixty-in-nineteen-years-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 19:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/17/how-to-go-from-zero-to-sixty-in-nineteen-years-meetup/</guid>
      <description>After meeting Woody in a number of workshops and presentations about MOB programming, it was an unique and interesting opportunity to watch him talk about a different topic. He gave an inspiring talk about randomness, confirmation bias, serendipity, learning, experimenting, or as he called it “stumbling purposely and purposeful stumbling”. All of these coming from his own life experience, with a melange of personal stories, wise words and simply beautiful drawings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 3 - 6 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/10/15/lean-agile-scotland-day-3-6-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/15/lean-agile-scotland-day-3-6-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>The third day of LAScot was a little bit shorter for me, because I chose to come back to Stockholm on the same day. That gave me just enough time to see the keynote and @JoakimSunden’s talk about the “Spotify Model”.
Keynote: Awesome Superproblems by Luke Hohmann (@ LukeHohmann) Luke’s keynote was very inspiring. He demonstrated how our experience in building products and services can be used in other domains and parts of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 2 - 5 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/10/12/lean-agile-scotland-day-2-5-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 17:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/12/lean-agile-scotland-day-2-5-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>One of the tricky parts of LAScot was getting hold of the tokens for tracks 3 to 5, which were not filmed and required a token to get access. Or you could “risk” it and drop by anyway, maybe someone changes his/her mind or there is some room left. In all the workshops I’ve been at, there were always extra people accommodated into the room.
These being said, on the first day I completely forgot about the tokens, although I was pretty early in the conference centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Agile Scotland - Day 1 - 4 Oct 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/10/09/lean-agile-scotland-day-1-4-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 19:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/09/lean-agile-scotland-day-1-4-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>This year was the first time I attended LAScot and I had high expectations from it. I wasn’t disappointed even just one bit!
I enjoyed the relaxed and friendly atmosphere. There is no right and there is no wrong, no superior or inferior, there’s just sharing, learning and lots of fruitful conversations. It’s the perfect environment for nurturing old friendships and growing new ones on the ground of common interests and a passion for the diverse fields that constitute and contribute to the knowledge work most of us are doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile is also about people</title>
      <link>/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 16:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</guid>
      <description>This has been probably said millions of times until now, but maybe it wouldn’t hurt to say it once more: agile is also about people.
The promise of agile is that, if applied “_properly_”, it will “accelerate development cycles, reveal code defects earlier, decrease overall project risk, and allow faster response to customer needs and changing business priorities” to quote one of the Google results.
And I don’t think anyone is really doubting that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coaching Agile Teams: A Companion for ScrumMasters, Agile Coaches, and Project Managers in Transition (Addison-Wesley Signature Series (Cohn)) by Lyssa Adkins, 2010</title>
      <link>/2016/08/07/coaching-agile-teams-a-companion-for-scrummasters-agile-coaches-and-project-managers-in-transition-addison-wesley-signature-series-cohn-by-lyssa-adkins-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/07/coaching-agile-teams-a-companion-for-scrummasters-agile-coaches-and-project-managers-in-transition-addison-wesley-signature-series-cohn-by-lyssa-adkins-2010/</guid>
      <description>Book details  * Author link: [http://www.coachingagileteams.com/](http://www.coachingagileteams.com/) * Amazon link: [https://www.amazon.com/Coaching-Agile-Teams-ScrumMasters-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321637704](https://www.amazon.com/Coaching-Agile-Teams-ScrumMasters-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321637704) * My rating: ★★★★★ (5/5)  Some thoughts In a world where agile is mostly understood as processes, Lyssa Adkins includes in it also the human part. So an agile coach doesn&amp;rsquo;t just take care of the process, but coaches and mentors the team and the people in it, to be better at agile, by also taking a look at the human side of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Guide Refresh July 2016</title>
      <link>/2016/07/29/scrum-guide-refresh-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 11:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/29/scrum-guide-refresh-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>On 6th of July, a refreshed version of the Scrum Guide was released in a live webinar by Ken Schwaber and Jeff Sutherland.
The refresh basically consists in adding the Scrum values into the guide, the values as they were featured in the last chapter of the first book on Scrum (Agile Software Development with Scrum). Ken and Jeff identified these values while working at Patient Keeper and consider them to be very important to a successful Scrum adoption in companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>agile info?</title>
      <link>/2016/06/11/agile-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/11/agile-info/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I added a few new sources of agile info (and not only) into my RSS reader and I would like to share them with you:
 * [https://www.reddit.com/r/agile/](https://www.reddit.com/r/agile/) * [https://www.reddit.com/r/softwaredevelopment/](https://www.reddit.com/r/softwaredevelopment/) * [http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/](http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/) * [http://blog.crisp.se/](http://blog.crisp.se/) * [http://www.svpg.com/articles/](http://www.svpg.com/articles/) * [http://www.jrothman.com/blogs/](http://www.jrothman.com/blogs/) * [http://ryanripley.com/agile-for-humans/](http://ryanripley.com/agile-for-humans/)  If you didn’t know, you can transform any reddit url in an RSS feed url by adding .rss at the end. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Cafe Episode 62 - Mary and Tom Poppendieck</title>
      <link>/2016/04/11/devops-cafe-episode-62-mary-and-tom-poppendieck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/11/devops-cafe-episode-62-mary-and-tom-poppendieck/</guid>
      <description>Listened recently to this episode from Devops Cafe Podcast which is loaded with useful information and references. Besides the ones found in the page of the episode, I extracted the ones below:
 * [Lean Product and Process Development](http://www.amazon.com/Lean-Product-Process-Development-Allen/dp/1934109134) * [Product Development Performance](http://www.amazon.com/Product-Development-Performance-Organization-Management/dp/0875842453) * [Implementing Lean Software Development: From Concept to Cash](http://www.amazon.com/Implementing-Lean-Software-Development-Concept/dp/0321437381) * [Value stream mapping](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Value_stream_mapping) * [The Lean Startup](http://www.amazon.com/The-Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous/dp/0307887898) * [Personal Kanban](http://www.amazon.com/Personal-Kanban-Mapping-Work-Navigating/dp/1453802266) * [Building Microservices](http://www.amazon.com/Building-Microservices-Sam-Newman/dp/1491950358) * [Two Pizza Team](http://www.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052970203914304576627102996831200) * [Adrian Cockroft](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t you do story mapping in your agile projects?</title>
      <link>/2016/02/28/why-dont-you-do-story-mapping-in-your-agile-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 18:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/28/why-dont-you-do-story-mapping-in-your-agile-projects/</guid>
      <description>Story maps is a concept made popular by Jeff Patton and he started using them professionally before he even started to call them story maps. They were born from the need of having a better way of approaching complex agile projects, one that gives them a better chance to be successful.
They&amp;rsquo;re not sliced bread But they&amp;rsquo;re really close. I&amp;rsquo;ve started using story maps a few months ago and I find them a very useful tool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>