<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal development on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/categories/personal-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal development on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 20:26:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/categories/personal-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights and storing knowledge</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/07/04/highlights-and-storing-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 20:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/07/04/highlights-and-storing-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago I was writing about a routine I setup to manage and refresh highlights from books and articles. In the meantime, I have adjusted it a little bit, removed some services and added some others. Let&#39;s start with the bits that didn&#39;t work that well.
Highlights from articles As much as I liked the flow with sending articles weekly from Pocket to Kindle using a service named aptly Pocket2Kindle, I soon became swamped with articles pending on my Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resurface highlights from books and articles you&#39;ve read in the past</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/03/04/resurface-highlights-from-books-and-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 20:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/03/04/resurface-highlights-from-books-and-articles/</guid>
      <description>In the last years, I&#39;ve been reading a fair amount of books. Besides that, I&#39;ve been wanting to read more interesting articles and blogs, which is why I started using Pocket for almost a year now. At the same time, I&#39;ve kept trying all kind of routines that would make me remember more from what I read. In the next paragraphs, I&#39;m going to describe what I am currently doing and although it is not perfect, it feels the best so far, considering I don&#39;t have much time to invest in revisiting these reads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On meditation and journaling</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 14:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</guid>
      <description>Meditation For some time now (months) I have been meditating and journaling every day. I find this combo very useful for keeping myself on track with what I want to achieve and also be more present and balanced during the day.
I started playing around with the idea of meditating several years ago when I read Search Inside Yourself by Chade-Meng Tan, but it didn’t stick. I tried it several times again in the more recent years and I found it hard to practice every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept gravity and let go of your anchors</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/02/accept-gravity-and-let-go-of-your-anchors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/02/accept-gravity-and-let-go-of-your-anchors/</guid>
      <description>There are a couple of concepts I learned about recently, while reading “Designing your life” by Bill Burnett and Dave Evans. These are not part of the main idea of the book, but I found them as powerful as they are simple.
Gravity problems A gravity problem is a problem that is not actionable. If you see gravity as a problem and you decide to fight it, to “solve” it, you will realise sooner or later that it is unsolvable and you would be far off better with accepting it as a reality and find ways to work around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three great books to start the year</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/04/23/three-great-books-to-start-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 18:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/04/23/three-great-books-to-start-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Every year, I manage to read one or two books that get my mind going and give me ideas that I could either apply right away or that set me on a larger path of discovery. One or two out of tens, or to be more specific, last year, out of thirty. I started to look into ways I could organise notes and ideas that I find in books in a better way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Enlightenment: How Meditation Works by Shinzen Young, 2016</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://www.shinzen.org Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Science-Enlightenment-How-Meditation-Works-ebook/dp/B01KUGQYJO My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts Mindfulness and meditation are trendy. Or maybe that’s just my impression. There are many trainings and meditation experts out there, luring you to the places of clarity and tranquility, ability of getting over stressful and painful experiences in an easier way and experiencing life in a richer way.
I don’t know from a personal experience this to be a truthful promise, but that doesn’t mean it is not true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits and every day work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/25/habits-and-every-day-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 18:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/25/habits-and-every-day-work/</guid>
      <description>After reading in the The Power of Habit about how militaries or football coaches use habits to train their soldiers or players to react fast in the field, I started wondering how much of this science we could use in our everyday “pencil-pushing” or “keyboard-smashing” knowledge work?
As Charles Duhigg puts it, a habit consists of three important elements: a cue, a routine and a reward. On top of that, you need a craving to drive the loop cue-routine-reward to repeat itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My reading routine</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/05/my-reading-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 14:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/05/my-reading-routine/</guid>
      <description>Fiction or non-fiction? I’m always on the lookout for new things, so I’m constantly reading and learning stuff. I noticed that I cannot read always non-fiction, because it is usually harder to digest, so I only do that in the morning (usually in the subway ride to work) when my mind is fresh.
At the same time, if I only read non-fiction, I feel like I am always thinking about the things I am reading and my mind doesn’t get to disconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My personal map</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/28/my-personal-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 08:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/08/28/my-personal-map/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Nikoletta&#39;s post and Jurgen Appelo&#39;s Management3.0 concept of Personal Maps, I decided to do one for myself. So if you want to know a bit more about me, go check it out, either above or at this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procrastinating by getting distracted</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/procrastinating-by-getting-distracted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 15:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/procrastinating-by-getting-distracted/</guid>
      <description>Attention is a precious thing these days. Emails, Facebook notifications, playlist notifications, colleague asking for help, loud neighbours, annoying ad and so many others, they are all running your power of concentration really low.
There are all kind of discussions about how knowledge workers have a hard time nowadays to produce &amp;lsquo;deep work&#39;, the kind of work and thinking that is required when trying to solve difficult and profound problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/02/stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/02/stuck/</guid>
      <description>Feeling stuck is not pleasant.
It feels like there&#39;s no direction to go towards to and there&#39;s not much to do. You get more and more frustrated with your current situation and you cannot think of anything else. You become obsessed.
Ironic, isn&#39;t it? To get stuck in your own thoughts. Because in reality very few situations are without exit. And I&#39;m not referring to those extreme cases here.
Every number of months or years you might get into a state where you know you have to change something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/25/so-whats-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 16:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/25/so-whats-next/</guid>
      <description>Here I am, at the end of the YourTurnChallenge! Uuuhuu, what a ride! __
I was pleasantly surprised to see that since about the half of the challenge I stopped using the list of subjects I prepared beforehand because I had other ideas I wanted to write about and those felt better than the ones on the list. That makes me feel very good about myself because I proved that I don&#39;t need to worry much about what to write as long as I write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 14:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>In a conversation with a friend (same friend, same conversation as a few days ago), he mentioned that everything that happens in the world is related basically to one question that each of us asks himself involuntarily: Who am I?
Some people identify with their job, with their hierarchy in the management ladder of a huge corporation. Some other identify with their religion or with their race or gender or &amp;hellip; you name it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have an idea</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 17:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>I have an idea about a revolutionary recipe website. Yeah, you read it right, a recipe website. Being a software engineer, you would think that it should be easy for me to build it and launch it, basically it&#39;s something I do every day for my employer. But as you might have found out, shipping is not that simple.
Stuck in preparation I had this idea for several years now and I started to make it happen, I think, about 4 or 5 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frustration</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/22/frustration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/22/frustration/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever felt like you&#39;ve been shoved into a corner and there&#39;s no way out? Well, there&#39;s always a way out, but maybe none that you would prefer taking? You could walk away at any time, but then you would loose all the work and effort you put into it. And then the rage fills you, because you feel helpless, handicapped. You don&#39;t like giving up, so you keep going, trying and trying and trying, maybe you will finally succeed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-preservation</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 17:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</guid>
      <description>I have thought many times why is it so difficult to admit that we were wrong. What makes it that hard to say &amp;ldquo;I&#39;m sorry, I was wrong&amp;rdquo;. Is it that important to always be right? Or is it just about not admitting that we were wrong?
&amp;ldquo;In fact, until we have to admit to someone that we were wrong, we aren&#39;t wrong, are we? I mean, that&#39;s all that matters, what the others think of us, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactive or Reactive</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/03/proactive-or-reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 08:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/03/proactive-or-reactive/</guid>
      <description>Just a few things I read this a couple of days ago about reactive/proactive:
&amp;ldquo;Our behaviour is a function of our decisions, not our conditions&amp;rdquo;. If we choose to blame others for our conditions, we become reactive. &amp;ldquo;Proactive people are driven by values - carefully thought about, selected and internationalised values&amp;rdquo; while &amp;ldquo;Reactive people are driven by feelings, by circumstances, by conditions, by their environment&amp;rdquo;.
Reactive language:
 * There&#39;s nothing I can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Bundle or how I started reading more fiction</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 17:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Intro I have to say, I usually don&#39;t read a lot of fiction or fantasy books, as in, I rarely go and search for a specific fiction book in a store. It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t like the genre, but I seem to feel guilty because I don&#39;t read something &amp;ldquo;serious&amp;rdquo; instead. There&#39;s also the search of something to read, going through top 10 lists, New York Times best sellers list and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfishness</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/14/selfishness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 18:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/14/selfishness/</guid>
      <description>It seems that people are selfish by nature. All our instincts teach us to take care of ourselves and then of our species. If we would be reduced to our set of primal instincts, I would expect things to be quite simple. The game of life is known by everyone and the natural selection wins as always.
Imagine that one of these primitive humans could be tamed, like any other animals, by a superior creature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you say no?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/16/do-you-say-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/16/do-you-say-no/</guid>
      <description>Cover picture from growingleaders.com
We all want to help other people, we like to be problem solvers, we want to be in the spotlight, no seems like a barrier
To start with a well-known geek joke[1], &amp;ldquo;there are 10 types of people in the world&amp;rdquo;, those who can say no and those who can not.
No(!), I&#39;m actually talking about those situations where you know you should say no, but you don&#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem solving and the random factor</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/27/problem-solving-and-the-random-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/27/problem-solving-and-the-random-factor/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A colleague of mine asked for my help, after spending hours on trying to figure out why he is getting the wrong results with his code. I went to his desk and in 5 minutes, problem was solved! You would be tempted to say, &amp;ldquo;Whoaaa, man, you&#39;re very good! Solving that dude&#39;s problem in a few minutes after he spent hours working it!&amp;quot;.
Well, actually I didn&#39;t do anything. My colleague fixed his problem on his own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme of the month: Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/08/theme-of-the-month-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/08/08/theme-of-the-month-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>I have been recently reading about performance and what makes you better. The term of &amp;lsquo;deliberate practice&amp;rsquo; popped up more than once.
I&#39;m halfway through the book Talent Is Overrated: What Really Separates World-Class Performers from Everybody Else by Geoff Colvin and I found quite some interesting things while reading it.
We all know that in order to get better at something we have to practice. Well, it seems that it is not enough and in order to get best results we should engage in something called &amp;lsquo;deliberate practice&amp;rsquo; in a study from the &amp;lsquo;90s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much are we lying to ourselves?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/16/how-much-are-we-lying-to-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/16/how-much-are-we-lying-to-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>Random thoughts about self-inflicted lies.
I think that each and every one of us lies to himself at least a few times a day. From the &amp;ldquo;I&#39;ll go pick up dry cleaning tomorrow, it&#39;s too cold today&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;He doesn&#39;t have a clue what he says, you&#39;re cool, he&#39;s just jealous&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;hellip;
People who don&#39;t accept critics are probably keeping themselves in some sort of pedestal, where nobody can touch them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contra</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/16/contra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/16/contra/</guid>
      <description>One of the main ideas of the famous TV show, House M.D., was that in order to generate good ideas, you have to challenge yourself or have people to challenge you at every step.
And I think this is the most valuable lesson which that show has to offer and it repeats it in every damn episode, for the duration of 8 seasons! It must be good!
Leaving House aside, challenge, if it&#39;s done in a constructive manner, it is very productive, otherwise it&#39;s just &amp;lsquo;contra&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2012/10/10/habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 07:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2012/10/10/habits/</guid>
      <description>We are creatures of habit. I’m sure you heard this expression before.

But it’s actually true. We need routines and habits to give structure to our life. Of course, there are a few rebels out there, who are decided to live every day in a different way, but I’m sure that even they have a routine in their craziness.
We build routines around things we HAVE to do (or feel uncomfortable about) and they start with small things that we LIKE to do, just to compensate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>