<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Vision on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/categories/the-vision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Vision on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 14:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/categories/the-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On meditation and journaling</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 14:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</guid>
      <description>Meditation For some time now (months) I have been meditating and journaling every day. I find this combo very useful for keeping myself on track with what I want to achieve and also be more present and balanced during the day.
I started playing around with the idea of meditating several years ago when I read Search Inside Yourself by Chade-Meng Tan, but it didn’t stick. I tried it several times again in the more recent years and I found it hard to practice every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accept gravity and let go of your anchors</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/02/accept-gravity-and-let-go-of-your-anchors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 19:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/12/02/accept-gravity-and-let-go-of-your-anchors/</guid>
      <description>There are a couple of concepts I learned about recently, while reading “Designing your life” by Bill Burnett and Dave Evans. These are not part of the main idea of the book, but I found them as powerful as they are simple.
Gravity problems A gravity problem is a problem that is not actionable. If you see gravity as a problem and you decide to fight it, to “solve” it, you will realise sooner or later that it is unsolvable and you would be far off better with accepting it as a reality and find ways to work around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three great books to start the year</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2018/04/23/three-great-books-to-start-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 18:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2018/04/23/three-great-books-to-start-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Every year, I manage to read one or two books that get my mind going and give me ideas that I could either apply right away or that set me on a larger path of discovery. One or two out of tens, or to be more specific, last year, out of thirty. I started to look into ways I could organise notes and ideas that I find in books in a better way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software down!!!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/08/06/software-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 14:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/08/06/software-down/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, my first impulse when the service I’m developing is malfunctioning is to jump right on it and try to fix it. But while I do that, I can’t help thinking about who is affected by it and how bad and if they will notice it. Then there’s the first five to ten minutes of the investigation, when I realise how far I am from finding a solution, yet, I keep thinking “Almost there, almost there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people - snapshot</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 04:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</guid>
      <description>To easily remember the main ideas of my previous post, Teams are made of people, I thought of a representative word and a short alternative description for each of them:
 Vision. The team has a vision of what it tries to accomplish. It should to be clear what is the team’s purpose accompanied by a “grand vision” that everyone understands and resonates with. Individuality. The team is aware of and respects the individual differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 17:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</guid>
      <description>I think this is quite an obvious thing to say. At the same time, it is quite common to forget what this fact means. What does it mean that this team that provides a service, or builds a product or works on a project, what does it mean that it is made of people? And to the extent of that, what does it mean that the users or the stakeholders are also people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile is also about people</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 16:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/07/agile-is-also-about-people/</guid>
      <description>This has been probably said millions of times until now, but maybe it wouldn’t hurt to say it once more: agile is also about people.
The promise of agile is that, if applied “properly”, it will “accelerate development cycles, reveal code defects earlier, decrease overall project risk, and allow faster response to customer needs and changing business priorities” to quote one of the Google results.
And I don’t think anyone is really doubting that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habits for reducing interruptions</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/04/19/habits-for-reducing-interruptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/04/19/habits-for-reducing-interruptions/</guid>
      <description>In most of the companies I worked so far, we usually get a lot of interruptions. Everything is deemed important and our attention is stretched super thin between all kind of distractions. In the beginning it feels good, we are busy and we are being helpful, but after a while it gets exhausting. And the flow of requests never ends.
One of the big issues with a large number of interruptions is that we are forced to make a lot of small decisions tens of times a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship: play for the long game</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/27/mentorship-play-for-the-long-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/27/mentorship-play-for-the-long-game/</guid>
      <description>One of the many wonderful game techniques I found out about in Yu-Kai Chou’s Actionable Gamification is about Mentorship (Game Technique #61).
Yu-Kai came up with a more elaborate “motivation framework” which has its roots in his research and other people’s research in why some games are so addictive. The Octalysis framework consists of 8 core drives that could be used to explain or design different experiences or products and how much they motivate people in one way or the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy at work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/19/autonomy-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 17:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/19/autonomy-at-work/</guid>
      <description>Full disclosure: I haven’t read Daniel Pink’s Drive yet, but that doesn’t mean I can’t talk about autonomy, one of the 3 elements of true motivation he writes about in his book.
If you ask any employer in the world right now, I hardly believe anyone will tell you (s)he wants to micro-manage people. So what does it mean to not micro-manage people? It means giving them the autonomy they need to do their job in the best way they consider doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product vision and technical vision and something extra</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/12/product-vision-and-technical-vision-and-something-extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/03/12/product-vision-and-technical-vision-and-something-extra/</guid>
      <description>Take into consideration the following scenarios:
Scenario 1 Caleb is a product owner which works with a software development team in a successful product company. Caleb has a grand vision for the product that he is responsible for in the company. It is a vision that will probably never see the light of day exactly in the shape he imagines it right now, but maybe somewhere along the lines. In order to make this vision happen, Caleb works closely together with Dave, the tech lead of the development team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you micro-manage much?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know about you, but in my experience until now, there were situations where I felt micro-managed. And I hated it. Badly. It frustrated me. I didn’t understand why I was treated like that and I didn’t like the implications it had on the perceived quality of my work.
Doesn’t my boss think I’m capable? If you’re someone who cares about their work, having a boss who micro-manages you is not a good sign.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>