<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your own podcast transcription service</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2020/01/12/make-your-own-podcast-transcription-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2020/01/12/make-your-own-podcast-transcription-service/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of very interesting podcasts out there that I like to listen to, as much as time allows me to do so. But I noticed that I don&#39;t recall much out of them and I feel the need to go through them again. It would be great if all podcasts came with a transcript, so I can quickly revisit the parts that interest me. Unfortunately, making transcripts to your podcasts can be quite expensive, which is why most authors don&#39;t do so or put them behind a paywall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here it comes!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/19/here-it-comes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 14:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/19/here-it-comes/</guid>
      <description>The quiet Before it arrives, everything is pretty calm. There&#39;s the occasional walker and the soothing sound of the fountain, but not much else. Everything else is synchronised with its arrival. The majestic metal runner that brings people to their destination.
You wouldn&#39;t expect anything grandiose to happen, judging by how everything looks like. Some beggars at the entrance of the supermarket, one or two shoppers jumping from one deal to another, a couple of bored taxis standing by in the station and a homeless drinking his life from cheap beer cans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/25/so-whats-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 16:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/25/so-whats-next/</guid>
      <description>Here I am, at the end of the YourTurnChallenge! Uuuhuu, what a ride! __
I was pleasantly surprised to see that since about the half of the challenge I stopped using the list of subjects I prepared beforehand because I had other ideas I wanted to write about and those felt better than the ones on the list. That makes me feel very good about myself because I proved that I don&#39;t need to worry much about what to write as long as I write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Live Deployment (Stories from Bitopia)</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/06/the-live-deployment-stories-from-bitopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 17:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/08/06/the-live-deployment-stories-from-bitopia/</guid>
      <description>It was a dark rainy night. You could hear some stray dogs howling, probably annoyed as well by the heavy rain. Everyone was at home. Well, except us, me and Marcel. We were getting ready for what was supposed to be my first live deployment since I joined Codis.
“It needs to be done during the night, when our users are busy fucking, living their pitiful worry-less lives! What do they care when we do updates, as long as everything WORKS!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>