<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 20:26:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights and storing knowledge</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/07/04/highlights-and-storing-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 20:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/07/04/highlights-and-storing-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago I was writing about a routine I setup to manage and refresh highlights from books and articles. In the meantime, I have adjusted it a little bit, removed some services and added some others. Let&#39;s start with the bits that didn&#39;t work that well.
Highlights from articles As much as I liked the flow with sending articles weekly from Pocket to Kindle using a service named aptly Pocket2Kindle, I soon became swamped with articles pending on my Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resurface highlights from books and articles you&#39;ve read in the past</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/03/04/resurface-highlights-from-books-and-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 20:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/03/04/resurface-highlights-from-books-and-articles/</guid>
      <description>In the last years, I&#39;ve been reading a fair amount of books. Besides that, I&#39;ve been wanting to read more interesting articles and blogs, which is why I started using Pocket for almost a year now. At the same time, I&#39;ve kept trying all kind of routines that would make me remember more from what I read. In the next paragraphs, I&#39;m going to describe what I am currently doing and although it is not perfect, it feels the best so far, considering I don&#39;t have much time to invest in revisiting these reads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My reading routine</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/05/my-reading-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 14:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/05/my-reading-routine/</guid>
      <description>Fiction or non-fiction? I’m always on the lookout for new things, so I’m constantly reading and learning stuff. I noticed that I cannot read always non-fiction, because it is usually harder to digest, so I only do that in the morning (usually in the subway ride to work) when my mind is fresh.
At the same time, if I only read non-fiction, I feel like I am always thinking about the things I am reading and my mind doesn’t get to disconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Bundle or how I started reading more fiction</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 17:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Intro I have to say, I usually don&#39;t read a lot of fiction or fantasy books, as in, I rarely go and search for a specific fiction book in a store. It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t like the genre, but I seem to feel guilty because I don&#39;t read something &amp;ldquo;serious&amp;rdquo; instead. There&#39;s also the search of something to read, going through top 10 lists, New York Times best sellers list and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>