<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/categories/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/categories/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The challenge of helping others</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/10/20/the-challenge-of-helping-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/10/20/the-challenge-of-helping-others/</guid>
      <description>A book I&#39;ve been reading lately revealed to me how tricky helping relationships can be, even though we put ourselves in such relationships several times every day and we don&#39;t even realise it. There are many things we do automatically successfully and we don&#39;t even think about it. Because we have been trained for many years by society and parents how to do it correctly according to the common rules. Helping others is no exception: we have been taught to help people around us that are in need and be receptive to others&amp;rsquo; pain and distress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people - snapshot</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 04:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/06/22/teams-are-made-of-people-summary/</guid>
      <description>To easily remember the main ideas of my previous post, Teams are made of people, I thought of a representative word and a short alternative description for each of them:
 Vision. The team has a vision of what it tries to accomplish. It should to be clear what is the team’s purpose accompanied by a “grand vision” that everyone understands and resonates with. Individuality. The team is aware of and respects the individual differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teams are made of people</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 17:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/05/22/teams-are-made-of-people/</guid>
      <description>I think this is quite an obvious thing to say. At the same time, it is quite common to forget what this fact means. What does it mean that this team that provides a service, or builds a product or works on a project, what does it mean that it is made of people? And to the extent of that, what does it mean that the users or the stakeholders are also people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you micro-manage much?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know about you, but in my experience until now, there were situations where I felt micro-managed. And I hated it. Badly. It frustrated me. I didn’t understand why I was treated like that and I didn’t like the implications it had on the perceived quality of my work.
Doesn’t my boss think I’m capable? If you’re someone who cares about their work, having a boss who micro-manages you is not a good sign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reality check</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/05/10/reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 10:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/05/10/reality-check/</guid>
      <description>Think of one of your employees. Imagine he asks you the following: how would you sell my job position to me, if I would be a candidate to be hired for it?
Would you be able to answer with an empty conscience?
What feedback would you get from your employee?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-preservation</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 17:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</guid>
      <description>I have thought many times why is it so difficult to admit that we were wrong. What makes it that hard to say &amp;ldquo;I&#39;m sorry, I was wrong&amp;rdquo;. Is it that important to always be right? Or is it just about not admitting that we were wrong?
&amp;ldquo;In fact, until we have to admit to someone that we were wrong, we aren&#39;t wrong, are we? I mean, that&#39;s all that matters, what the others think of us, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make a change</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/24/lets-make-a-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 18:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/11/24/lets-make-a-change/</guid>
      <description>Some of these things are so simple that are easy to ignore, other are a little bit too abstract to act on them right away. It depends on each of us to act on the things we believe in, to make it our mission to fight for our ideas. Millions of books have been written about these subjects, yet most of the modern workers continue to ignore them. I’m going to add another drop to the ocean of recipes of presumed success, here it goes, take it with a bit of hope:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes a leader</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/19/what-makes-a-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 08:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/19/what-makes-a-leader/</guid>
      <description>Like I probably said before, I read quite a lot of books, especially business and self-help books. I found out a few weeks ago about Daniel Goleman&amp;lsquo;s new book, What makes a leader?. The book is basically a collection of posts he did on Harvard Business Review along the years, starting with the one that has the same title as the book and was initially published in 1998.
The trouble with all these books is that if you don&#39;t do something concrete with them right away, you&#39;ll probably forget most of their content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>