<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading notes on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/reading-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading notes on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/reading-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Chiri&#39;s reading notes - issue 3, feb &#39;20</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2020/03/01/reading-notes-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2020/03/01/reading-notes-3/</guid>
      <description>This month in my reading seems to have been dominated by one topic: capitalism and economic growth. A topic more and more popular due to the growing separation between rich and poor and impact on the environment. Spiced it up with some spy stories, strange societies who got rid of capitalism but also free will, tricking Google Maps with a cart, happiness, innovation in business, the future and a discussion about space and science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Chiri&#39;s reading notes - issue 2, jan &#39;20</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2020/02/02/reading-notes-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 06:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2020/02/02/reading-notes-2/</guid>
      <description>This was another pretty diverse month when it comes to reading: there’s more about ageing, strange stories about policemen and bicycles, leadership and change or leadership for change, how you need to fall in order to raise yourself, and some small bits and pieces about depression, philosophy, gene editing, productivity tools and several others. Hope you enjoy them!
 Lifespan, Why We Age—and Why We Don&#39;t Have To, by David Sinclair As a follow-up to David&#39;s podcast with Kevin Rose, I read his book, wanting to find out more details about his theory on ageing and I was not disappointed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Chiri&#39;s reading notes - issue 1, dec &#39;19</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2019/12/31/reading-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 06:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2019/12/31/reading-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by several newsletters I follow and read regularly, like Brain Food by Farnam Street, I decided to start my own little experiment in sharing some of the things I learn during the month in a newsletter. Just in time before the end of the year, the first issue of Reading Notes is out! Talking about software development gone bad, gone good, entrepreneurship and parenting, ageing and genetics and a system of taking notes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>