<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 12:49:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Radical Candor: Be a Kick-Ass Boss Without Losing Your Humanity by Kim Scott, 2017</title>
      <link>/2017/09/03/radical-candor-be-a-kick-ass-boss-without-losing-your-humanity-by-kim-scott-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 12:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/03/radical-candor-be-a-kick-ass-boss-without-losing-your-humanity-by-kim-scott-2017/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: https://www.radicalcandor.com Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Radical-Candor-Kim-Scott/dp/B01KTIEFEE My rating: ★★★★★  Some thoughts Radical Candor or something with similar principles is essential for everyone to use in the work place to create connections with the others and learn and improve. It is also something that can require a lot of conscious effort to accomplish. But also to some it comes naturally in part. While reading the book, I remembered situations from my experience when I could&amp;rsquo;ve reacted in a better way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Enlightenment: How Meditation Works by Shinzen Young, 2016</title>
      <link>/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://www.shinzen.org Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Science-Enlightenment-How-Meditation-Works-ebook/dp/B01KUGQYJO My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts Mindfulness and meditation are trendy. Or maybe that’s just my impression. There are many trainings and meditation experts out there, luring you to the places of clarity and tranquility, ability of getting over stressful and painful experiences in an easier way and experiencing life in a richer way.
I don’t know from a personal experience this to be a truthful promise, but that doesn’t mean it is not true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever</title>
      <link>/2017/02/06/the-coaching-habit-say-less-ask-more-change-the-way-you-lead-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 18:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/06/the-coaching-habit-say-less-ask-more-change-the-way-you-lead-forever/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://www.boxofcrayons.biz/the-coaching-habit-book/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01BUIBBZI/ My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts The book is an elaboration of a simple trick: try to listen more and ask questions, rather than directly giving advice. I enjoyed the lecture of the book and the explanations of the 7 questions. Like all this kind of advice, I believe it is worth starting practicing the original questions to get an understanding of what are their effects and then start coming up with your own questions that have the same effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership and Self-Deception: Getting Out of the Box by The Arbinger Institute</title>
      <link>/2016/12/19/leadership-and-self-deception-getting-out-of-the-box-by-the-arbinger-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 18:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/19/leadership-and-self-deception-getting-out-of-the-box-by-the-arbinger-institute/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: https://arbinger.com/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00GUPYRUS/ My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts I think The Arbinger Institute are on to something. It is still not 100% clear for me how someone gets in the box in the workplace, but I can definitely recognise the situation where one would throw trash at the company, without a clear understanding of why and what is the actual problem. It is easier to throw trash at something or someone else than criticising yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actionable Gamification - Beyond Points, Badges, and Leaderboards</title>
      <link>/2016/10/23/actionable-gamification-beyond-points-badges-and-leaderboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/23/actionable-gamification-beyond-points-badges-and-leaderboards/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://yukaichou.com/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Actionable-Gamification-Beyond-Points-Leaderboards/dp/1511744049 My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts I like the Octalysis framework and its concepts. I think it makes sense and can be applied in pretty much anything related to people. The book has A LOT of well known examples which makes it easier to understand the basics.
I find it pretty difficult to internalize the meaning and the effects of the core drives, especially when combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum: The Art of Doing Twice the Work in Half the Time by Jeff Sutherland, 2014</title>
      <link>/2016/09/29/scrum-the-art-of-doing-twice-the-work-in-half-the-time-by-jeff-sutherland-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 17:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/29/scrum-the-art-of-doing-twice-the-work-in-half-the-time-by-jeff-sutherland-2014/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: https://www.scruminc.com/ Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Scrum-Doing-Twice-Work-Half/dp/038534645X My rating: ★★★☆☆(3&amp;frasl;5)  Some thoughts I enjoyed reading this book, it is quite an easy read, which you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect after you go through the Scrum Guide. It goes through the origins of Scrum and the concepts behind it. It is filled with success stories, projects that were not going that well (now that&amp;rsquo;s an understatement), like the Sentinel project of the FBI, and how applying Scrum to them improved their outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coaching Agile Teams: A Companion for ScrumMasters, Agile Coaches, and Project Managers in Transition (Addison-Wesley Signature Series (Cohn)) by Lyssa Adkins, 2010</title>
      <link>/2016/08/07/coaching-agile-teams-a-companion-for-scrummasters-agile-coaches-and-project-managers-in-transition-addison-wesley-signature-series-cohn-by-lyssa-adkins-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/07/coaching-agile-teams-a-companion-for-scrummasters-agile-coaches-and-project-managers-in-transition-addison-wesley-signature-series-cohn-by-lyssa-adkins-2010/</guid>
      <description>Book details  * Author link: [http://www.coachingagileteams.com/](http://www.coachingagileteams.com/) * Amazon link: [https://www.amazon.com/Coaching-Agile-Teams-ScrumMasters-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321637704](https://www.amazon.com/Coaching-Agile-Teams-ScrumMasters-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321637704) * My rating: ★★★★★ (5/5)  Some thoughts In a world where agile is mostly understood as processes, Lyssa Adkins includes in it also the human part. So an agile coach doesn&amp;rsquo;t just take care of the process, but coaches and mentors the team and the people in it, to be better at agile, by also taking a look at the human side of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</title>
      <link>/2015/01/19/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 18:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/19/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people/</guid>
      <description>By accident, like most of the books I read, I stumbled upon Stephen Covey&amp;rsquo;s book, The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those books, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough to read them, or at least not just once, but you also should think deeply about the ideas in them and apply them into your life.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time I mention Covey&amp;rsquo;s book, I have shared fragments from it and even gave an extremely short summary of the main concepts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So good they can&#39;t ignore you by Cal Newport</title>
      <link>/2013/07/22/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-by-cal-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/22/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-by-cal-newport/</guid>
      <description>With all the books out there that tell you to follow your passion, whichever that is, this book feels like a fresh breeze in a hot summer
Finding his/her passion is something that everyone dreams about. This is one of the main dilemmas when you are a freshman.
The labour market has changed in the last decade or so and there&amp;rsquo;s more need for people with initiatives and who are creative, in any field of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great books</title>
      <link>/2013/03/24/great-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/24/great-books/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read some really great books in the last couple of years. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of those books.
The value of these books is relative to whatever the reader takes out from them. Just putting them in the &amp;lsquo;read&amp;rsquo; list of Goodreads won&amp;rsquo;t make the reader rich, successful or in any way different.
Already read  * **Difficult Conversations: How to Discuss What Matters Most** by Douglas Stone, Bruce Patton, Sheila Heen * One of the best books I have read in the last period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>val team = geek&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>/2012/11/17/val-team-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 09:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/17/val-team-geek/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: a typical geek is not known for his social skills, best manners or his exquisite taste in clothes. Of course, most of the geeks are not typical either, but again most of them would prefer to be buried in bad code than holding a presentation or buy clothes for a fancy party with a dress code.
Team Geek. A Software Developer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Working Well with Others|Brian W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Angel&#39;s Game by Carlos Ruiz Zafón</title>
      <link>/2012/09/27/the-angels-game-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/27/the-angels-game-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</guid>
      <description>Shortly after finishing The Shadow Of The Wind, I received the second novel from the series.

David Martin. A boy that becomes a man too soon, due to some tragic events. He starts working for a living at a small age and for a low wage, constantly pressured by his condition and his dark past. What he doesn’t know is that the future is even darker, maybe too dark, if you ask me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficult conversations</title>
      <link>/2012/09/16/difficult-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/16/difficult-conversations/</guid>
      <description>We all have difficult conversations everyday, be it with someone who steps in front of you in line or with your boss asking for a raise. Sometimes they don&amp;rsquo;t end as we would have liked it, right?

How many times we think that the other party is to blame of the result? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s normal, our self-conservation instinct does that to protect us of bad feelings. But that is not generally a good thing, because at the same time cancels any type of self analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow Of The Wind by Carlos Ruiz-Zafón</title>
      <link>/2012/09/01/the-shadow-of-the-wind-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/01/the-shadow-of-the-wind-by-carlos-ruiz-zafon/</guid>
      <description>One of the best books I read in the last couple of months, it has all the right elements to be a successful novel.
I found out about this novel from a tweet of one of the people I&amp;rsquo;m following. The tweet contained a quote that made me curious:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;People are evil. — Not evil, Fermín objected. Moronic, which isn&#39;t quite the same thing. &amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;  Now, after reading the book, I think this is one of the quotes that best describes the ultimate cause of the tragedy from this story Zafón presents to us: human nature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>