<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quick thoughts on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/categories/quick-thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quick thoughts on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 09:49:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/categories/quick-thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What newsletters I happily open my mailbox to?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/15/what-newsletters-i-happily-open-my-mailbox-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 09:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/10/15/what-newsletters-i-happily-open-my-mailbox-to/</guid>
      <description>I have the impression that the general feeling towards the notion of newsletters is somewhere close to idea of spam. Lots of ads, poor content and usually showing up in your inbox without requesting it or without realising you have subscribed to it (check the tiny little checkboxes at the bottom of the forms!)
But there are exceptions, here are the newsletters that I am always happy to receive and actually look forward to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>drunkenpmradio - Having Empathy For Your Project - w/ Patrice Colancecco Embry [podcast]</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/drunkenpmradio-having-empathy-for-your-project-w-patrice-colancecco-embry-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 16:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/drunkenpmradio-having-empathy-for-your-project-w-patrice-colancecco-embry-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Link: https://alexchiri.com/post/drunkenpmradio-having-empathy-for-your-project-w-patrice-colancecco-embry-podcast
My notes: Treat a project with empathy.
As a PM talk about good things with &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo; and about negative with &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;.
As a PM you have to be positive about the project and believe that will succeed.
Do not talk bad about the project until the end. Allow yourself in the post-mortem to hate the project a little bit.
You should be positive and shove the negative at the end without looking like you fake it or you are not genuine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octalysis, self-deception, Cynefin and Slickyboards - Interesting! (Nov&#39;16)</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/octalysis-self-deception-cynefin-and-slickyboards-interesting-nov16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 16:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/11/06/octalysis-self-deception-cynefin-and-slickyboards-interesting-nov16/</guid>
      <description>Dust has settled on my blog lately. Writing stuff for the Internet is not my priority, no matter how much I enjoy it. I did decide to try something though: to briefly write about interesting things I found out every month. Like a newsletter about nothing and about everything, a mixed bag of new and old things I think are worth sharing. So here it is: Interesting!, Nov’16 edition!
Contents  * Octalysis, an actionable gamification framework * Self-deception and why it is so important for leaders and not only * Cynefin (pronounced _ku-nev-in_) framework for decision making * Slickyboards and Slickynotes, cheap convenient alternative for home whiteboards and static post-its  Games and what can we learn from why we play them Understanding what motivates people to do things is a pretty interesting problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFH 043: The Agile Mindset with Gil Broza</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/09/13/afh-043-the-agile-mindset-with-gil-broza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 16:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/09/13/afh-043-the-agile-mindset-with-gil-broza/</guid>
      <description>Link: http://ryanripley.com/afh-043-the-agile-mindset-with-gil-broza-podcast/
As my memory doesn&#39;t seem to help me a lot with all this content around, I decided to start to create notes for podcasts as well. A little bit behind with my book notes and my podcast listening, but I&#39;m starting to catch up.
Notes
Too many agile implementations are not greatly exciting and not yielding great results
Most important for cultivating an agile mindset
 * Start with basic awareness of what it is - what do we mean when we say agile * Why do we want these things - agile is not just for better/cheaper/faster, but to delight the customers  A lot of people think that agile is the new standardised process and it is not a process nor standardised</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum Guide Refresh July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/29/scrum-guide-refresh-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 11:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/29/scrum-guide-refresh-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>On 6th of July, a refreshed version of the Scrum Guide was released in a live webinar by Ken Schwaber and Jeff Sutherland.
The refresh basically consists in adding the Scrum values into the guide, the values as they were featured in the last chapter of the first book on Scrum (Agile Software Development with Scrum). Ken and Jeff identified these values while working at Patient Keeper and consider them to be very important to a successful Scrum adoption in companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFH 042: The Grows Method for Adopting Agile Software Develpoment</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/16/afh-042-the-grows-method-for-adopting-agile-software-develpoment-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/07/16/afh-042-the-grows-method-for-adopting-agile-software-develpoment-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Link: http://ryanripley.com/afh-042-the-grows-method-for-adopting-agile-software-development-podcast/
As I&#39;ve heard someone recently say, the amount of new Agile methods or methodologies is competing with the number of new JavaScript frameworks that pop up every now and then. When it comes to new Agile methods, they all usually have certain things in common (the Agile principles) but they come with a twist.
When it comes to Grows, as far as I understood from the podcast, the twist comes from the short feedback loops, involvement of executive roles, the tech best practices and the gradual development of the method in 5 stages (modelled after the Dreyfus Model of Skill Acquisition).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>agile info?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/11/agile-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/06/11/agile-info/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I added a few new sources of agile info (and not only) into my RSS reader and I would like to share them with you:
 * [https://www.reddit.com/r/agile/](https://www.reddit.com/r/agile/) * [https://www.reddit.com/r/softwaredevelopment/](https://www.reddit.com/r/softwaredevelopment/) * [http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/](http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/) * [http://blog.crisp.se/](http://blog.crisp.se/) * [http://www.svpg.com/articles/](http://www.svpg.com/articles/) * [http://www.jrothman.com/blogs/](http://www.jrothman.com/blogs/) * [http://ryanripley.com/agile-for-humans/](http://ryanripley.com/agile-for-humans/)  If you didn’t know, you can transform any reddit url in an RSS feed url by adding .rss at the end. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Project Management Triangle must die!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/17/the-project-management-triangle-must-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 09:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/17/the-project-management-triangle-must-die/</guid>
      <description>John Ferguson Smart and Jan Molak in an article I stumbled upon today:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&amp;quot;On time, in scope and in budget&amp;quot;. This is the refrain of countless project managers on their LinkedIn profiles: it is the badge of the successful project manager, and they wear it with pride. It is also a misguided and dangerous idea that invariably encourages a short-sighted and bureaucratic mind-set, detrimental to both project teams and the organisations they serve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Cafe Episode 62 - Mary and Tom Poppendieck</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/devops-cafe-episode-62-mary-and-tom-poppendieck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/04/11/devops-cafe-episode-62-mary-and-tom-poppendieck/</guid>
      <description>Listened recently to this episode from Devops Cafe Podcast which is loaded with useful information and references. Besides the ones found in the page of the episode, I extracted the ones below:
 * [Lean Product and Process Development](http://www.amazon.com/Lean-Product-Process-Development-Allen/dp/1934109134) * [Product Development Performance](http://www.amazon.com/Product-Development-Performance-Organization-Management/dp/0875842453) * [Implementing Lean Software Development: From Concept to Cash](http://www.amazon.com/Implementing-Lean-Software-Development-Concept/dp/0321437381) * [Value stream mapping](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Value_stream_mapping) * [The Lean Startup](http://www.amazon.com/The-Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous/dp/0307887898) * [Personal Kanban](http://www.amazon.com/Personal-Kanban-Mapping-Work-Navigating/dp/1453802266) * [Building Microservices](http://www.amazon.com/Building-Microservices-Sam-Newman/dp/1491950358) * [Two Pizza Team](http://www.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052970203914304576627102996831200) * [Adrian Cockroft](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective memory</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/selective-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 11:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/selective-memory/</guid>
      <description>Madiha Bhatti about basically racism:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t create a sense of urgency, foster a sense of purpose.</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/dont-create-a-sense-of-urgency-foster-a-sense-of-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/20/dont-create-a-sense-of-urgency-foster-a-sense-of-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Kimber Lockhart on a sense of purpose:
A sense of purpose is immersion in our cause, and allowing that exposure to motivate action. A sense of purpose is about going faster and smarter toward a mission we all see clearly. It’s about using good judgment because we all understand the short and long term implications of our actions on what we’re creating together. A strong sense of purpose manifests when a software engineer watches a potential customer struggle with a workflow and stays late to make the changes that make it easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next week I’m going to Jfokus. Are you coming also?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/04/next-week-im-going-to-jfokus-are-you-coming-also/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 17:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/02/04/next-week-im-going-to-jfokus-are-you-coming-also/</guid>
      <description>Freshly moved to Stockholm, I am glad to go to Jfokus next week. There are quite a few talks, so it&#39;s good to be prepared. Here are the talks or workshops I&#39;m planning to attend to in each day:
Monday, 8th Feb  * 09:00 - 12:30: **Introduction to microservices**, Chris Richardson, Room C1 * 13:30 - 17:00: **Mob Programming Workshop**, Woody Zuill, Room C4  Tuesday, 9th Feb  * 09:15 - 10:30: **IoT Keynote: IoT - an evolution from Internet of Screens to Internet of Things**, Pawel Ostropolski - Intel, Room C1 * 11:00 - 11:15: **Presentation: Microservices: From dream to reality in forty five minutes**, Holly Cummins - IBM, Room A1 **Presentation: Moving Renewable Energy Embedded Systems Into the Cloud**, Mark Heckler - Pivotal * 13:00 - 13:50: **Presentation: Modelling Microservices at Spotify**, Petter Måhlén - Spotify, Room A1 * 14:00 - 14:50: **Presentation:How to defeat feature gluttony?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The client and the customer</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2016/01/24/the-client-and-the-customer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 08:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2016/01/24/the-client-and-the-customer/</guid>
      <description>Seth Godin explains the difference between a client and a customer
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;The customer buys (or doesn&#39;t buy) what you make. The client asks you to make something. The customer has the power to choose, but the client has the power to define, insist and spec. &amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;  It&#39;s an important distinction to make. I&#39;ve heard these terms being used pretty often with simply the meaning of the person/company that pays for a service or a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacation and work</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/28/vacation-and-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 05:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/28/vacation-and-work/</guid>
      <description>I am always wondering how would it be if people wouldn&#39;t take holidays anymore.
Holidays always seem like the pleasant parts of life, where you get to travel, to spend more time with your family, to enjoy yourself more, to &amp;ldquo;recharge your batteries&amp;rdquo;. Once you&#39;re back to work, you need to readjust to the chaos, the routine and all that &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; entails.
Why does it have to be like this? Why can&#39;t you work and do holiday activities on a continuous basis, therefore removing the need for holidays?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of (my) social media</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/22/future-of-my-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 12:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/22/future-of-my-social-media/</guid>
      <description>After sharing The Four Horsemen video (predictions about Google, Amazon, Facebook, Apple) on LinkedIn, I was asked by one of my connections if I would be willing to join him in preparing a blog that wants to predict the future of social media. Although I think it&#39;s a great idea (him who holds the power of information is always ahead), I declined, simply because I&#39;m no social media expert and more important, not an analyst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links and attention</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/14/links-and-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 12:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/03/14/links-and-attention/</guid>
      <description>I was reading the other day in some blinks (summaries of non-fiction books) from The Shallows, the following:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;Trying to juggle so much stimulus at once results in a loss of concentration, and makes it nearly impossible to read and extract information from long online texts. In fact, one experiment has shown that the more links a text includes, the less information participants could comprehend and remember after reading it. &amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;  And then I thought of my 7 habits article that I wrote a month or so ago, it has 21 (twenty one) links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, there&#39;s streaming</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/02/19/so-theres-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 18:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/02/19/so-theres-streaming/</guid>
      <description>There are were and are a lot of discussions about Spotify not paying fair the artists for the number of streams that their creations get in the music streaming network. Now, to be honest, I don&#39;t know if Spotify is fair or not, there&#39;s plenty of pro articles as well as against this topic, but that&#39;s besides the point.
Let&#39;s say that Spotify doesn&#39;t pay fair, let&#39;s just assume that this is the uncontestable truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 14:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>In a conversation with a friend (same friend, same conversation as a few days ago), he mentioned that everything that happens in the world is related basically to one question that each of us asks himself involuntarily: Who am I?
Some people identify with their job, with their hierarchy in the management ladder of a huge corporation. Some other identify with their religion or with their race or gender or &amp;hellip; you name it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should things be simple, when they can be complicated?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/20/why-should-things-be-simple-when-they-can-be-complicated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 18:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/20/why-should-things-be-simple-when-they-can-be-complicated/</guid>
      <description>Or… should it be the other way around?
I’m always amazed about the amount of effort some people put in things that don’t need to be complicated. There is a general misconception that thorough and good work is recognised by the size of the deliverable. Therefore, insecure people will have the tendency to produce more and more complicated results, in an effort to compensate, to seem what they’re not.
Of course, we are often raised and educated that more is better, especially in communist educational systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/14/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 05:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/14/success/</guid>
      <description>I was having a discussion with one of my friends the other day…
7 habits I started telling him all about this good book[1] I just finished and that I found quite inspiring: you have these 7 habits everyone needs to develop, 3 for yourself, 3 for your relations with the others and 1 to grease the wheels for the others 6, to keep the thing going.
You have to be proactive, to be aware that you can make the choice of how you act, no matter what environment you’re in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactive or Reactive</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/03/proactive-or-reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 08:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/03/proactive-or-reactive/</guid>
      <description>Just a few things I read this a couple of days ago about reactive/proactive:
&amp;ldquo;Our behaviour is a function of our decisions, not our conditions&amp;rdquo;. If we choose to blame others for our conditions, we become reactive. &amp;ldquo;Proactive people are driven by values - carefully thought about, selected and internationalised values&amp;rdquo; while &amp;ldquo;Reactive people are driven by feelings, by circumstances, by conditions, by their environment&amp;rdquo;.
Reactive language:
 * There&#39;s nothing I can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes a leader</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/19/what-makes-a-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 08:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/10/19/what-makes-a-leader/</guid>
      <description>Like I probably said before, I read quite a lot of books, especially business and self-help books. I found out a few weeks ago about Daniel Goleman&amp;lsquo;s new book, What makes a leader?. The book is basically a collection of posts he did on Harvard Business Review along the years, starting with the one that has the same title as the book and was initially published in 1998.
The trouble with all these books is that if you don&#39;t do something concrete with them right away, you&#39;ll probably forget most of their content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joel on software, work and management</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/25/joel-on-software-work-and-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/25/joel-on-software-work-and-management/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you&#39;ve heard about Joel Spolsky, or maybe his blog domain joelonsoftware.com sounds familliar. No? Nevermind!
He seems a smart and open minded person and he managed to (co-)found quite some cool companies, which gave birth to some really cool products (Stack Exchange or Trello anyone?)
He recently came back from his blogging retirement with an article about Trello. While I think Trello is a very good product, I was a bit more interested in the company culture reminded in his article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfishness</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/14/selfishness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 18:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2014/07/14/selfishness/</guid>
      <description>It seems that people are selfish by nature. All our instincts teach us to take care of ourselves and then of our species. If we would be reduced to our set of primal instincts, I would expect things to be quite simple. The game of life is known by everyone and the natural selection wins as always.
Imagine that one of these primitive humans could be tamed, like any other animals, by a superior creature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who knows what dinking is?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/04/who-knows-what-dinking-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/09/04/who-knows-what-dinking-is/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading an interesting book about the history of biking in the Netherlands written by an American. I have encountered some interesting facts.
First of all, what is dinking? I intend to clear this mystery as fast as possible, with a quote from TheFreeDictionary:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;dink adj (Clothing &amp;amp; Fashion) Scot and northern English dialect neat or neatly dressed vb Austral and NZ chiefly children&#39;s slang a. (tr) to carry (a second person) on a horse, bicycle, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You gotta&#39; love the Sunday evening news</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/07/22/you-gotta-love-the-sunday-evening-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/07/22/you-gotta-love-the-sunday-evening-news/</guid>
      <description>I had the dark thought of watching the news while visiting my relatives and friends in Romania and it happened to be a Sunday (yesterday). Here are a few of the subjects presented:
 * Son cuts his father&#39;s penis because he found him with his daughter in law naked, in bed! They presented extensive interviews of the neighbours and friends of the family affected by this damn affair. * The President was craving for some beer so he crashed a festival close to Bucharest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is a dance</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/02/08/life-is-a-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/02/08/life-is-a-dance/</guid>
      <description>I have discovered Alan Watts a few days ago and since then I have been going through the Youtube videos with his lectures. I like his way of putting things into words, it&#39;s a pleasure to listen and to think about his ideas. Here&#39;s one of my favorites that could be resumed to one simple idea: carpe diem!
[embed]https://www.youtube.com/embed/29atSZKbmS4[/embed]
I have tried to make a transcript of this video, couldn&#39;t grasp a couple of words, sorry for that!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More or less</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/05/more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/01/05/more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>A bit of history I started using my parents old russian vinyl player when I was a bit older than 3 years old (or so I was told). We had a few tens of vinyls, most of them &amp;lsquo;classics&amp;rsquo; like Harry Belafonte, Elton John, Roxette, Abba and a bunch of children stories recorded for the radio, sometime in the &amp;lsquo;60s or &amp;lsquo;70s.
You could guess which were my favorites at that time, I knew them by heart and a day wouldn&#39;t pass without the player &amp;lsquo;booming&amp;rsquo; with children stories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>