<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cooking on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/tags/cooking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cooking on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:49:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/tags/cooking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple, light(-ish) and tasty evening snack</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/05/simple-light-ish-and-tasty-evening-snack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/08/05/simple-light-ish-and-tasty-evening-snack/</guid>
      <description>Fancy a delicious evening snack, but you don&#39;t want to feel too guilty about the extra calories?
Then I present you the Crunchy-Tomato-Garlicky-Madness!!! Isn&#39;t that a tongue twister? Never-mind, I still have to work on the marketing part, I&#39;ll figure it out later.
Ingredients Now go grab from your local grocery store the following and get munching (2 portions):
 1 large sized tomato (with the least plastic as possible) crackers / hard bread (more fibre, less unhealthy stuff) 3-4 cloves of fresh green garlic (not that frozen ages ago Chinese crap) chives dried tomato paste (optional, brings some extra flavour kick, also calories) shredded old cheese flakes (optional, but&amp;hellip;) olive oil lemon juice / vinegar salt  The process Get 2 crackers and put a thin layer of the tomato paste on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look ma&#39;, I cooked again!</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/18/look-ma-i-cooked-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/18/look-ma-i-cooked-again/</guid>
      <description>After the last special, here comes another one. My mother used to cook a version of the following recipe when I was little. Ladies and gents, I give you Chiri Mama&#39;s Beef Delight!
Ingredients I don&#39;t know much about from what part of the cow every piece of meat comes from, so forgive me for not being really specific:
 * 600 grams of beef meat (I like it to have a bit of fat, gives more flavor) * 3 big peppers * 250 grams (basmati) rice (if you use a different rice, you might want to put less rice) * 1 big onion * 5-6 garlic cloves * half a glass of red wine * cooking olive oil * grilled paprikas (as a side dish)  How to First things first and that means you have to cut that cow down, medium slices, not too big, but not too small, you want to distinguish them from the rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers can cook</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/09/developers-can-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/11/09/developers-can-cook/</guid>
      <description>Not that there&#39;s anyone there believing that developers cannot cook, but there&#39;s no harm in stating the obvious from once in a while[1]. So, here you go, Chiri&#39;s Chicken &#39;Sort Of&#39; Stew recipe:
Ingredients Now, you can make a stew out of pretty much anything, but today I chose the following ingredients:
 * 500 grams of chicken * 3 big peppers * 500 grams of &#39;shrooms (champignons) * 1 big onion * 1 can of peeled tomatoes * 5-6 garlic cloves  How to This is not rocket science, when it comes to stews, you have to put all the stuff together in a pot and let them boil for a while and you&#39;re done!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>