<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About me on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>/categories/about-me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About me on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 14:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/about-me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On meditation and journaling</title>
      <link>/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 14:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/16/on-meditation-and-journaling/</guid>
      <description>Meditation For some time now (months) I have been meditating and journaling every day. I find this combo very useful for keeping myself on track with what I want to achieve and also be more present and balanced during the day.
I started playing around with the idea of meditating several years ago when I read Search Inside Yourself by Chade-Meng Tan, but it didn’t stick. I tried it several times again in the more recent years and I found it hard to practice every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Enlightenment: How Meditation Works by Shinzen Young, 2016</title>
      <link>/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/14/the-science-of-enlightenment-how-meditation-works-by-shinzen-young-2016/</guid>
      <description>Book details  Author link: http://www.shinzen.org Amazon link: https://www.amazon.com/Science-Enlightenment-How-Meditation-Works-ebook/dp/B01KUGQYJO My rating: ★★★★☆  Some thoughts Mindfulness and meditation are trendy. Or maybe that’s just my impression. There are many trainings and meditation experts out there, luring you to the places of clarity and tranquility, ability of getting over stressful and painful experiences in an easier way and experiencing life in a richer way.
I don’t know from a personal experience this to be a truthful promise, but that doesn’t mean it is not true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When you&#39;re moving houses...</title>
      <link>/2015/10/18/when-youre-moving-houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 15:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/18/when-youre-moving-houses/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; you get this strange feeling, you sort of feel disoriented.
Maybe in our case was because things happened quite fast. Today we are in the apartment we lived for 3.5 years, 2 days later is completely empty and the morning after we hand in the keys to the agency, get in our car and drive away.
I was never really attached to things or places, but you develop habits and routines like using the same place to put your keys when you get in or the path you always take when doing your morning jogging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you and goodbye Holland, heeellooo Sweden!</title>
      <link>/2015/08/27/thank-you-and-goodbye-holland-heeellooo-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 07:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/27/thank-you-and-goodbye-holland-heeellooo-sweden/</guid>
      <description>Immigrant life: reboot! So here we are, changing the type of the statistic we are. After 4 years and a few months since my wife and I were counted as moving in to The Netherlands and Amsterdam, we will be counted as leaving.
There&amp;rsquo;s nothing out of the ordinary in our decision. Different groups of friends told me that&amp;rsquo;s the norm, after 4 years in the country of tulips, you either stay quite longer or you leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot in NL</title>
      <link>/2015/08/03/hot-in-nl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 16:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/03/hot-in-nl/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I noticed since I&amp;rsquo;ve been living in The Netherlands is that when the weather is hot, most drivers are going crazy. Aggressive over takes, speeding, poor checks on turns, not even talking about signalling! It&amp;rsquo;s like a drivers gone mad convention.
But despite this behaviour there aren&amp;rsquo;t many accidents or at least not many serious accidents[1] in The Netherlands yearly. Maybe also because there aren&amp;rsquo;t too many hot days in the Dutch summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of (my) social media</title>
      <link>/2015/03/22/future-of-my-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 12:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/03/22/future-of-my-social-media/</guid>
      <description>After sharing The Four Horsemen video (predictions about Google, Amazon, Facebook, Apple) on LinkedIn, I was asked by one of my connections if I would be willing to join him in preparing a blog that wants to predict the future of social media. Although I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great idea (him who holds the power of information is always ahead), I declined, simply because I&amp;rsquo;m no social media expert and more important, not an analyst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 14:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/24/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>In a conversation with a friend (same friend, same conversation as a few days ago), he mentioned that everything that happens in the world is related basically to one question that each of us asks himself involuntarily: Who am I?
Some people identify with their job, with their hierarchy in the management ladder of a huge corporation. Some other identify with their religion or with their race or gender or &amp;hellip; you name it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have an idea</title>
      <link>/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 17:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/23/i-have-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>I have an idea about a revolutionary recipe website. Yeah, you read it right, a recipe website. Being a software engineer, you would think that it should be easy for me to build it and launch it, basically it&amp;rsquo;s something I do every day for my employer. But as you might have found out, shipping is not that simple.
Stuck in preparation I had this idea for several years now and I started to make it happen, I think, about 4 or 5 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frustration</title>
      <link>/2015/01/22/frustration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/22/frustration/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever felt like you&amp;rsquo;ve been shoved into a corner and there&amp;rsquo;s no way out? Well, there&amp;rsquo;s always a way out, but maybe none that you would prefer taking? You could walk away at any time, but then you would loose all the work and effort you put into it. And then the rage fills you, because you feel helpless, handicapped. You don&amp;rsquo;t like giving up, so you keep going, trying and trying and trying, maybe you will finally succeed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m joining the YourTurnChallenge</title>
      <link>/2015/01/17/im-joining-the-yourturnchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/17/im-joining-the-yourturnchallenge/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you heard, maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t, but there&amp;rsquo;s a new challenge in town!
It&amp;rsquo;s called Your Turn Challenge and it&amp;rsquo;s initiated by Winnie, the Special Projects Lead for Seth Godin. Now, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter who drives it, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting for some time to increase the number of my blog posts and get them coming in a more regular fashion.
The challenge consists in blogging every day of next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success</title>
      <link>/2015/01/14/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 05:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/14/success/</guid>
      <description>I was having a discussion with one of my friends the other day…
7 habits I started telling him all about this good book[1] I just finished and that I found quite inspiring: you have these 7 habits everyone needs to develop, 3 for yourself, 3 for your relations with the others and 1 to grease the wheels for the others 6, to keep the thing going.
You have to be proactive, to be aware that you can make the choice of how you act, no matter what environment you’re in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make a change</title>
      <link>/2014/11/24/lets-make-a-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 18:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/24/lets-make-a-change/</guid>
      <description>Some of these things are so simple that are easy to ignore, other are a little bit too abstract to act on them right away. It depends on each of us to act on the things we believe in, to make it our mission to fight for our ideas. Millions of books have been written about these subjects, yet most of the modern workers continue to ignore them. I’m going to add another drop to the ocean of recipes of presumed success, here it goes, take it with a bit of hope:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another unboxing of a Myo armband</title>
      <link>/2014/11/07/yet-another-unboxing-of-a-myo-armband/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 16:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/07/yet-another-unboxing-of-a-myo-armband/</guid>
      <description>This is probably the gazillionth unboxing of a Myo that surfaced the Internet, so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother you with too many comments. Let the images speak for themselves! :D
P.S. The unlock gesture, &amp;ldquo;pinky to thumb&amp;rdquo;, is killing me. Need.more.practice!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Bundle or how I started reading more fiction</title>
      <link>/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 17:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/15/the-story-bundle-or-how-i-started-reading-more-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Intro I have to say, I usually don&amp;rsquo;t read a lot of fiction or fantasy books, as in, I rarely go and search for a specific fiction book in a store. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I don&amp;rsquo;t like the genre, but I seem to feel guilty because I don&amp;rsquo;t read something &amp;ldquo;serious&amp;rdquo; instead. There&amp;rsquo;s also the search of something to read, going through top 10 lists, New York Times best sellers list and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AsciiDoc writing</title>
      <link>/2014/02/23/asciidoc-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/02/23/asciidoc-writing/</guid>
      <description>Context, context, it&amp;rsquo;s all about context I started a little while ago to write a book. Yeah, I know, who would have thought, right? But that&amp;rsquo;s besides the point.
Initially I used a writer specific app for Mac called Ulysses and while the app is really great, it has two disadvantages:
 * it is available only for Mac (and maybe in the future for iOS) * not geeky enough (I know this is a stretch for a second reason, but hey!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing up</title>
      <link>/2014/01/02/standing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/01/02/standing-up/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I started using an improvised standing desk at home. I&amp;rsquo;m sure some of you at least heard about the article about the 22$ standing desk made using an IKEA coffee table.
I&amp;rsquo;m a classical couch potato most of the time and I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of many sports, definitely not a fan of gyms or running, especially in a gym. I&amp;rsquo;m also convinced that just by exchanging a sitting position with a standing position you accomplish almost nothing, exchanged an evil with maybe a smaller evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firecrackers and What the Hell?!!?!?</title>
      <link>/2014/01/01/firecrackers-and-what-the-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/01/01/firecrackers-and-what-the-hell/</guid>
      <description>_Cover picture from ebeijing.gov.cn_
After my &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo; to different lands, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t fail to notice that Romania is not the only country where firecrackers can be heard intensively for the whole freakin&amp;rsquo; month of December. Children and children_not_anymore light large quantities of firecrackers on the streets, like some sort of way making themselves noticed, I guess?
Traditions I knew there is some sort of tradition in China, something about keeping evil spirits at bay, but my knowledge ended there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile publishing with Octopress and RaspberryPi</title>
      <link>/2013/10/20/mobile-publishing-with-octopress-and-raspberrypi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/10/20/mobile-publishing-with-octopress-and-raspberrypi/</guid>
      <description>Preamble A few weeks ago scriptogr.am decided to suddenly change how their Markdown processor worked, making any HTML embedded in the Markdown posts worthless, among other things. So I woke up that my 2-readers-blog was looking like s**t, with content not being displayed[1], all because of the changes scriptogr.am did without any warning before.
These actions triggered some tweets to be sent, although I was already decided to move from scriptogr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourists in Amsterdam - Part I</title>
      <link>/2013/10/01/tourists-in-amsterdam-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/10/01/tourists-in-amsterdam-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Being surprised by the incredible weather this weekend, we decided to walk around Amsterdam a bit, like any tourist would do.
Here&amp;rsquo;s our journey from this Saturday, accompanied by photos and some explanations(TREASURE MAP), follow the pointers on the map to get an idea where the photos were taken:
1 Our starting point, close to Centraal Station, near the luxurious Amrath Hotel and its 7 Seas restaurant. Amazing pillow of clouds in the background, incredible weather for this end of September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch countryside</title>
      <link>/2013/09/24/dutch-countryside/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/24/dutch-countryside/</guid>
      <description>A view from the countryside near the Zaanse Schans, a park known for its functional wind mills and traditional Dutch landscapes.

Taken on 1st of October, 2011 in The Netherlands
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playful squirrels</title>
      <link>/2013/09/15/playful-squirrels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/15/playful-squirrels/</guid>
      <description>A pair of playful squirrels somewhere on the Petřín hill, Prague, Czech Republic

Taken on 17th of September, 2008 in Czech Republic
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain cross</title>
      <link>/2013/09/11/mountain-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/11/mountain-cross/</guid>
      <description>The cross on the &amp;ldquo;Caraiman&amp;rdquo; peak, Romania

Taken on 26th of December, 2006 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunset</title>
      <link>/2013/09/08/sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/08/sunset/</guid>
      <description>The end of one of those hot summer days, &amp;ldquo;Lacul Morii&amp;rdquo;, Bucharest, Romania

Taken on 9th of June, 2009 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country side</title>
      <link>/2013/09/07/country-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/07/country-side/</guid>
      <description>I have been going through our photos recently and thought that some are nice to share. So I am gonna start doing this quite often. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first:

Taken on 5th of June, 2010 in Romania
click on the image for the full size version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who knows what dinking is?</title>
      <link>/2013/09/04/who-knows-what-dinking-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/04/who-knows-what-dinking-is/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading an interesting book about the history of biking in the Netherlands written by an American. I have encountered some interesting facts.
First of all, what is dinking? I intend to clear this mystery as fast as possible, with a quote from TheFreeDictionary:
&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;dink adj (Clothing &amp;amp; Fashion) Scot and northern English dialect neat or neatly dressed vb Austral and NZ chiefly children&#39;s slang a. (tr) to carry (a second person) on a horse, bicycle, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giethoorn</title>
      <link>/2013/09/01/giethoorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/01/giethoorn/</guid>
      <description>One of the most picturesque villages I have visited until now in the Netherlands, only for the ones who don&amp;rsquo;t feel threatened by boats and water.
Giethoorn, this village in the province of Overijssel, is often called the Venice of the North and while far from me to make this kind of appreciations (I have never been to Venice, yet), I can say it is definitely one of the objectives you should not miss while in Holland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A life protecting barrier for the Rotterdam area</title>
      <link>/2013/08/25/a-life-protecting-barrier-for-the-rotterdam-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 07:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/25/a-life-protecting-barrier-for-the-rotterdam-area/</guid>
      <description>I have visited recently the Maeslantkering surge barrier in the Hoek van Holland area, near Rotterdam. It is an impressive construction with an important role: to protect lives.
But before I tell you more about the barrier, here&amp;rsquo;s a short introduction about The Delta Project.
The reason After the big flood in Jan-Feb 1953 (in Dutch is called watersnoodramp) and the 1836 people who died because of it, things became clear for the Netherlands[1]: they needed to be better prepared for this kind of events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme of the month: Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>/2013/08/08/theme-of-the-month-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/08/theme-of-the-month-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>I have been recently reading about performance and what makes you better. The term of &amp;lsquo;deliberate practice&amp;rsquo; popped up more than once.
I&amp;rsquo;m halfway through the book Talent Is Overrated: What Really Separates World-Class Performers from Everybody Else by Geoff Colvin and I found quite some interesting things while reading it.
We all know that in order to get better at something we have to practice. Well, it seems that it is not enough and in order to get best results we should engage in something called &amp;lsquo;deliberate practice&amp;rsquo; in a study from the &amp;lsquo;90s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You gotta&#39; love the Sunday evening news</title>
      <link>/2013/07/22/you-gotta-love-the-sunday-evening-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/22/you-gotta-love-the-sunday-evening-news/</guid>
      <description>I had the dark thought of watching the news while visiting my relatives and friends in Romania and it happened to be a Sunday (yesterday). Here are a few of the subjects presented:
 * Son cuts his father&#39;s penis because he found him with his daughter in law naked, in bed! They presented extensive interviews of the neighbours and friends of the family affected by this damn affair. * The President was craving for some beer so he crashed a festival close to Bucharest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gone static!</title>
      <link>/2012/12/29/gone-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 07:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/29/gone-static/</guid>
      <description>Having a small blog where you can ramble about whatever you want should be a simple thing, right? I mean you don&amp;rsquo;t pay much to the host, they have installation scripts for any platform you like, you just buy a domain (if you want) and you start writing! Well, that&amp;rsquo;s only in theory, at least for me.
It all started a few months ago with my domain alexchiri.ro just disappearing from the records of my host at that time, icebluehost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>