<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-awareness on alexchiri.com</title>
    <link>https://alexchiri.com/tags/self-awareness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-awareness on alexchiri.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:55:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexchiri.com/tags/self-awareness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you micro-manage much?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2017/02/20/do-you-micro-manage-much/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know about you, but in my experience until now, there were situations where I felt micro-managed. And I hated it. Badly. It frustrated me. I didn’t understand why I was treated like that and I didn’t like the implications it had on the perceived quality of my work.
Doesn’t my boss think I’m capable? If you’re someone who cares about their work, having a boss who micro-manages you is not a good sign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-preservation</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 17:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2015/01/21/self-preservation/</guid>
      <description>I have thought many times why is it so difficult to admit that we were wrong. What makes it that hard to say &amp;ldquo;I&#39;m sorry, I was wrong&amp;rdquo;. Is it that important to always be right? Or is it just about not admitting that we were wrong?
&amp;ldquo;In fact, until we have to admit to someone that we were wrong, we aren&#39;t wrong, are we? I mean, that&#39;s all that matters, what the others think of us, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much are we lying to ourselves?</title>
      <link>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/16/how-much-are-we-lying-to-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexchiri.com/2013/03/16/how-much-are-we-lying-to-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>Random thoughts about self-inflicted lies.
I think that each and every one of us lies to himself at least a few times a day. From the &amp;ldquo;I&#39;ll go pick up dry cleaning tomorrow, it&#39;s too cold today&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;He doesn&#39;t have a clue what he says, you&#39;re cool, he&#39;s just jealous&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;hellip;
People who don&#39;t accept critics are probably keeping themselves in some sort of pedestal, where nobody can touch them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>